<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>[review] Backblaze, cloud backup</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20130109_review-backblaze-cloud-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20130109_review-backblaze-cloud-backup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/logo_backblaze.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Backblaze&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;52&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-271&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started using computers, I have had a mixed relation with backups. They are too much hassle to deal with, they fail, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough space. But since the internet connections are able to handle all data I produce now, I decided to start using cloud backup. I&amp;rsquo;v chosen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com&#34; title=&#34;Online Backup &amp;#038; Data Backup Software&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Backblaze cloud backup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had and still have a fully installed and running local backup system. But it took me a while to figure out an easy way to have a offsite backup for my photography. The problem is that having an off site backup used to be a lot of work, I tried several ways, but never found a way that worked reliably and wasn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only easy way, was and still is by uploading everything, but the problem in Belgium was that there were up and download limits set by the providers. Even today on the &amp;#8220;unlimited&amp;#8221; packages there still is a kind of restriction, it is around 500 gb to 1TB a month depending on the area you live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-backblaze:e148ee00a4cf976b17c9ce8fe109987d&#34;&gt;Why Backblaze?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After extensively researching the different solutions, I decide to go with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com&#34; title=&#34;Online Backup &amp;#038; Data Backup Software&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;, because of the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup external drives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throttle upload speed of your data when needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship backup drives worldwide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only 4$ a month if you choose the 2 year plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlimited backup space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I found, there are no other services that offer all these options for that money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-does-it-work:e148ee00a4cf976b17c9ce8fe109987d&#34;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works great, after subscribing and paying with your credit card, you download and install the program for your OS. Backblaze will start to upload data from your internal drives. If you want to add more drives, just select it in the preferences pane. If you have upload limits, you can choose to throttle the speed and Blackblaze gives you an estimate how much it will upload during a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few figures to give you an idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.2 TB data backed up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial backup took 3.5 months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored main OS X data once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored 35 GB in a zip-file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;is-it-good:e148ee00a4cf976b17c9ce8fe109987d&#34;&gt;Is it good?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it took almost 4 months of backing up, it was no hassle, Backblaze just worked. Restoring was just a matter of selecting the files I wanted, waiting for the zip to be generated and then downloading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not all good, the restore process sucks. You&amp;rsquo;ll get all your files back, but it&amp;rsquo;s up to you to put them all back where they belong. That&amp;rsquo;s no fun, let me tell you. You have to deal with permissions, finding the correct folder and so on. Another annoyance, is the fact that after the restore, my secondary internal drive was no longer recognized as being the same drive, so it had to be backed up again, like the replaced primary drive. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion:e148ee00a4cf976b17c9ce8fe109987d&#34;&gt;Conclusion?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backblaze is a great solution for an off site backup, but it takes a while to get all your data backed up, my suggestion let me send you guys a drive with my data for an extra cost, like crashplan does. When you have to restore, it&amp;rsquo;s all manual labour. I would suggest that they implement some sort of restore program that does most of the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the remarks I have, I&amp;rsquo;m a satisfied &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com&#34; title=&#34;Online Backup &amp;#038; Data Backup Software&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Backblaze cloud backup&lt;/a&gt; user and would recommend it to everybody&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wasn’t forced to write this blogpost, everything in here is my own view, the content wasn’t reviewed by any departement of the brands mentioned in here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/logo_backblaze.gif&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/logo_backblaze.gif&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[review] Kingston 3K hyperX SSD</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20121020_review-kingston-3k-hyperx-ssd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20121020_review-kingston-3k-hyperx-ssd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: after 5 months this Kingston 3K hyperX SSD completely died on me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/hyperx.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kingston 3K HyperX SSD&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-267&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of june, my girflfriend (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saravdv.be&#34; rel=&#34;friend muse&#34; title=&#34;Saravdv: there are no endings, only new beginnings&#34;&gt;SaraVdV&lt;/a&gt;) got a mail from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kingston.com&#34; title=&#34;Kingston Technology&#34; rel=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Kingston&lt;/a&gt; if she and I wanted to test a new SSD drive from Kingston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some mailing back and forth, because Sara and I both work on mac&amp;rsquo;s, Kingston send us both a 256GB HyperX 3K SSD drive. It comes in a nice package, with an external usb enclosure and it&amp;rsquo;s own screwdriver. Which is always very handy. The drives we received were 2.5&amp;#8243; drives, but included in the package you buy, there&amp;rsquo;s also a 3.5&amp;#8243; bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it would be easier from me to put the drive in the MacBook pro 15&amp;#8243; begin 2009 I have, than to put it in an iMac. I started with that computer, the drive is as easy to install as any drive. However when I booted the mac and started installing OS X I ran into some problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first the install of OS X stalled a couple of times, when I finally managed to install it correctly, I had a 25 sec spinning beachball every 2 minutes. However, because we had review drives, I contacted Kingston directly and started to work out the problem with Mario, on of the engineers at Kingston who developed the drive. Turns out that there is an incompatibility between the nvidia SATA I controller in the MacBook 5.1 and the driver for SATA II or III SSD&amp;rsquo;s in OS X leopard or later. This makes that every time there is a lot of writing activity to the disk that the controller locks the OS for a while untill the buffers are cleared. So I ended up restoring this MacBook to it&amp;rsquo;s original config. This is not a fault of the kingston drive but an Apple problem, because I also experienced the same behaviour with another brand of SSD&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my debacle with the drive in the Macbook 5.1, I also installed the drive in Sara&amp;rsquo;s iMac which is not too big of a hassle if you follow all the guides online for replacing a drive in an iMac. I have not had any problems with installing the drive and reinstalling OS X, nor has Sara experienced any problems since the drive was installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July I purchased myself a new 13&amp;#8243; MacBook pro and installed the HyperX SSD in that computer. No problems, everything installs and works perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performance wise, everything seems a lot quicker on the iMac of Sara, boot times improved a lot. Every program launches faster and the drive behaves very well under pressure. We didn&amp;rsquo;t do any graphs or charts, because in the end it all comes down to how you preceive the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the MacBook 13&amp;#8243; I did some testing. Without SSD it cold booted in 34 seconds, after install of the SSD it cold boots in 8secs. That&amp;rsquo;s just amazing. It feels more instant now then waking my iPad first generation from sleep. Programs are launching very fast, lightroom which is the most important program for me, launches in less then 3 seconds in grid view. It all feels very snappy and instant. I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a beachball in months. Reboots are only necessary for updates from the OS. It just works and feels fast. It does what I expected an SSD to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nicest surprise is that we may keep the drives, so I got a nice upgrade for my new MacBook thanks to Kingston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t forced to write this blogpost, everything in here is my own view, the content wasn&amp;rsquo;t reviewed by any departement of the brands mentioned in here. I did however receive a compensation for this post. So decide for yourself how much value you want to attribute to this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/hyperx.jpg&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/hyperx.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Tutorial] Setting up WDS with Apple airports</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20120130_tutorial-setting-up-wds-with-apple-airports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20120130_tutorial-setting-up-wds-with-apple-airports/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE: in minutes of me posting this tutorial, my airport utility got an update to v6.0 and all I said is obsolete, my WDS network still works, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet how to set it up correctly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-11.46.31.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-11.46.31.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Airport_admin_utility&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-197&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over here we have a nice setup for our wireless network and playing music in all the rooms of our house. It&amp;rsquo;s supported by Apple airports. As you can see in the above screenshot. We use an Airport extreme as the router and 3 Airport expresses as relays. Last saturday evening however, disaster struck and our Airport extreme died. Well it did not die completely, it stopped serving internet through the wifi connections and there was only connection via ethernet connections. The wifi clients however could still connect, authenticate and got an ip-address, but there it all stopped. I tried everything to restore the connections, but despite all my efforts for about 3 hours. Rebooting, resetting, hard resetting nothing worked. So I setup a temporary solution and went out today to get a new Airport extreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get to the technical part of this article. How do you setup a network of 4 airports across the house on the same network with wpa2 security enabled? The first and most important step is to hard reset all the airports, the only way to do that if the airports don&amp;rsquo;t come straight from the box is to hold down the little reset button while pluggin in the airport. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know how, check this &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.apple.com/kb/ht3728&#34; title=&#34;Reset airport&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;support-page&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/&#34; title=&#34;Apple website&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;configure-the-base-station-or-wds-main:f0747a94ba74626be30e9712b67e6fe6&#34;&gt;Configure the base station or WDS main&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start by selecting manual configuration in the airport utility, don&amp;rsquo;t use the wizard, as you will not be able to setup WDS. On the next screen, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a couple of tabs, but none of them shows WDS, at least when you have a recent airport extreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now setup your Base Station like always, fill out the name, choose a password, &amp;#8230; under the Base Station tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next tab is the Wireless tab, this is 1 of the 2 tabs where all the magic will happen.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-21.35.43.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-21.35.43.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2012-01-30 at 21.35.43&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-203&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the dropdown menu next to &amp;#8220;Wireless Mode&amp;#8221; select &amp;#8220;Participate in a WDS network&amp;#8221;, if you don&amp;rsquo;t see it, hold down the &amp;#8220;option&amp;#8221; key, it will magically appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You setup your network as always, but make sure you select the checkbox &amp;#8220;Allow this network to be extended&amp;#8221;, leave the Radio mode on Automatic, choose WPA/WPA2 Personal, choose a password, go to the Wireless Network Options, set your country and leave all the rest. (&lt;em&gt;Hint:&lt;/em&gt; Write down all settings, we&amp;rsquo;ll need them later)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next is the WDS tab, that has appeared after you selected &amp;#8220;Participate in a WDS network&amp;#8221; in the previous step. Select &amp;#8220;WDS main&amp;#8221; in the dropdown from &amp;#8220;WDS Mode&amp;#8221;. Select the checkbox next to &amp;#8220;Allow wireless clients&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-21.47.50.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-21.47.50.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2012-01-30 at 21.47.50&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-209&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fill in the Airport ID&amp;rsquo;s of the soon to be remotes, you find the airport ID&amp;rsquo;s on the bottom of the airport it should be a string of 12 alphanumeric characters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That are all the steps for the configuring the base station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;configure-the-wds-remotes:f0747a94ba74626be30e9712b67e6fe6&#34;&gt;Configure the WDS remotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For configuring the remotes, repeat steps 1 till 3 exactly as in configuring the WDS main station. Make sure you have all the wireless settings exactly the same, as for the WDS main station. Make sure you did not miss any setting and if you must choose a channel set it to 11, because otherwise the remote station can&amp;rsquo;t connect with the WDS main.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-22.16.46.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2012-01-30 at 22.16.46&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-211&#34; /&gt;][4]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To finish the setup, go to the WDS tab and choose for &amp;#8220;WDS remote&amp;#8221; in the drop down next to &amp;#8220;WDS Mode&amp;#8221;. Select the checkbox next to &amp;#8220;Allow wireless clients&amp;#8221; and fill in the Airport ID of the &amp;#8220;WDS main&amp;#8221;, update and test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repeat the steps for the airport remote for as many times you need it. You should now be able to use the network and if you activated airplay under &amp;#8220;Music&amp;#8221; you should be able to play music through every airport with boxes or a headphone connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A last piece of advice, if you configured a airport and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t connect or shows up, put in a ethernet cable so that you can access it again. This will save you a lot of time, because the only other option is hard resetting the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-22.16.46.png&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-22.16.46.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#iThankSteve</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20111006_ithanksteve/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20111006_ithanksteve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This image on the homepage of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com&#34; title=&#34;Apple&#34;&gt;Apple.com&lt;/a&gt;says it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/Screen-Shot-2011-10-06-at-01.54.24.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2011-10-06 at 01.54.24&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-186&#34; /&gt;][2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at name apple gave the image, it gives you a very clear hint at how they see their founder. A hero, he was and still is one of my personal heroes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I will not mourn, I will honor his life as he did himself. Watch his commencement speech: &amp;#8220;How to live before you die&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/Screen-Shot-2011-10-06-at-01.54.24.png&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/Screen-Shot-2011-10-06-at-01.54.24.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logitech Magic</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110930_logitech-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110930_logitech-magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I got invited to the logitech magic event in Belgium together with some other bloggers. We rode out to Arquennes about 30 minutes from Brussels in Henegouwen. On arrival we were greeted with a glass of champagne and a short explanation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/wim_wauters&#34; title=&#34;Wim Wauters, on Twitter&#34; rel=&#34;contact met&#34;&gt;@wimwauters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images&#34; width=&#34;455&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-178&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got a tour around all the different products and in the mean time, there was a contest organized. I saw some nice products, but the most are not suited for me, because I have a fondness of the keyboards and mice/trackpads from Apple. The keys are just nicer from apple then any other keyboard I have used. However the accessoires for the ipad were very interesting, sadly enough the most interesting ones, like the keyboard cover are not suited for my iPad 1. But I can understand why a company developing products for Apple lines, are developing for the current versions alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contest had a pretty interesting take, because Logitech and Hill and Knowlton anticipated that we would cheat.  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:-)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;So they had a guess question included, which was how many tweets with the logitechmagic tag would be posted between 20 and 22h during the evening. As everybody was working together on finding the answers to the questions this actually was the only relevant question to receive the prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The range of prices was impressive, there was a surround system with a value of 350 euro to mice of 30 euro. But at least everybody got a price. I managed to get a set of Logitech 600vi in-ear phones. I&amp;rsquo;m currently testing them and I have to say the are amazingly great. These earphones are from the ultimate ear line, which is the same product line where a lot of professional musician are wearing headphones from during their concerts. The pair Sara and I got have a price value of 109 euro, which for me is very steep. That price means I would have never bought them myself, because I have a very bad track record with headphones. They tend to lay around and get tangled, ripped, get loose connections and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These seem very nicely and sturdy designed, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how they handle my abuse in the long run. The sound experience is quite impressive. I get a wide range of tones without any distortion or scrambling. The nice part is that there is a whole range of foam and plastic tips so you can choose the ones that fit your ear very nicely. I have a rather small ear channel and most tips don&amp;rsquo;t fit my ears, but the ones with the logitech ear phones actually fit my ear quite comfortable. I&amp;rsquo;m wearing them already several hours in a row, without getting any problems with having them falling out of my ear or without any discomfort. So my initial experience with these in-ear phones is very positive. So thanks a lot Logitech for a quite expensive goodie of good quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images.png&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of an era: Steve Jobs</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110825_the-end-of-an-era-steve-jobs-steps-down-as-ceo-of-apple-inc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110825_the-end-of-an-era-steve-jobs-steps-down-as-ceo-of-apple-inc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/steve-jobs1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;steve-jobs1&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; height=&#34;287&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-170&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a huge Apple fanboy, it&amp;rsquo;s a very sad day for me. Steve Jobs just announced his resignation as a CEO of Apple inc. Below you find the most significant part from his resignation letter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always said if there ever came a day when I could no longer meet my duties and expectations as Apple’s CEO, I would be the first to let you know. Unfortunately, that day has come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steve Jobs &amp;#8211; Resignation Letter august 24, 2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that Steve&amp;rsquo;s health was on a bad streak, starting with his pancreas cancer in 2006, his liver transplant in 2009 and the indefinite leave of absence due to health issues. Every keynote we saw a sleeker and sleeker Steve at this rate, he would be no more than a skeleton by the release of the iPhone 6. But I hoped that Steve would recover and kick some more butt in the years to come. Sadly that won&amp;rsquo;t be true anymore. Let&amp;rsquo;s just hope, that Steve can now focus on his health a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I say, the end of an era? A look at his track record, which reads like a good novel and is a string of successes, says it all. The story starts in 1976 with the release of the Apple I, a computer built in a garage by 2 very young guys, dreaming that one day they could earn a profit from it. Little would they know that was the beginning of a dream come true. Although Wozniak left Apple and Jobs was fired in the nineties and hired back afterwards, in which time he founded, build and make Pixar huge. Now Apple not only has produced great products, but it has also become the biggest company in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Jobs now resigning as CEO I still believe in Apple and they will keep on producing great products, but there won&amp;rsquo;t be anymore iconic black turtle necks, no more casual &amp;#8220;There&amp;rsquo;s one more thing&amp;#8221; to drop a bomb on a market. I fear that the cult of mac, will no longer exist, it has lost it leader. Apple will probably become a dull company that still makes great products, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t have me sitting in suspense during a keynote what they will announce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off course Jobs is not without fault, I&amp;rsquo;m the first to admit it, but he is kind of a hero for me. Creating a company from scratch and making it this big, but still maintaining the suspense when announcing something new. There is no other company that I know of where one man had such an impact on the development, announcement and sales of a product that nobody needed before it was announced. It also takes a great man, to resign due to health reasons from the company you built from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that one day, I can look back at my life and say I made an impact, as did Steve Jobs, my personal hero business wise. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t has to be as significant as Steve&amp;rsquo;s impact, but I would like to know that I have done well according to my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So hereby I salute you, Steve, you are a great man and leader. Take care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/steve-jobs1.jpeg&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/steve-jobs1.jpeg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of the Samsung Navibot VCR8855</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110127_review-of-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110127_review-of-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After more than 2 months using the Navibot, I want to give you a review. Let me say, we&amp;rsquo;re pretty pleased with the Robot vacuum cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it&amp;rsquo;s not a total solution for cleaning, it does a very good job keeping the house clean, when you set it on a daily routine. It takes a structured path, which takes it through the most part of the room. During it&amp;rsquo;s path, it tries to cover the whole area, but misses some spots. Luckily it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take the same path everyday and does the missed spots the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a week we empty the container containing the dust and hairs,. So it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require a lot of maintanance but whenever you forget about putting away all toys for the cat or the floorcloths, we use as doormats, something is bound to get stuck in the rotating brushes. Then the robot stops and starts beeping, until you fix the problem, that&amp;rsquo;s annoying and drives our cat crazy when we aren&amp;rsquo;t at home. But apart from that, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get trapped under furniture, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t wrecks anything around the home. It only bumps into the furniture that has legs that are smaller than 5cm because it is in the blind spot of the sensors. Even when it does bump into your furniture, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really damages it, because of the rubber bumpers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only very annoying thing about the robot is whenever you use the guards, it gets confused because the beam of the guard spreads wider then you intend and that leaves areas around the guard without cleaning. Our robot also had a little defect, which broke the system that makes the back brush rotate and we had to send it in for repair. Since then it drives around and cleans the whole area very good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a decent robot vacuum cleaner, then this is definitely what you need. It does a really good job keeping the house clean, without you lifting a finger, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not perfect but it&amp;rsquo;s a great aid. For us it is a great tool and definitely cheaper than paying a cleaning lady. So yes, it&amp;rsquo;s an expensive buy, but it will pay off after a while, because maintenance is not expensive at all. Even after 2 months we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to change any of the brushes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unboxing the Garmin Forerunner 210</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20101129_unboxing-the-garmin-forerunner-210/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20101129_unboxing-the-garmin-forerunner-210/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I received the Garmin Forerunner 210 I ordered of &lt;a href=&#34;http://garmin.mijngpsshop.be&#34; title=&#34;Mijn gpsshop&#34;&gt;mijngpsshop.be&lt;/a&gt;. I made an unboxing movie, which you can see here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/17244907&#34;&gt;Unboxing Garmin Forerunner 210&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/pitslamp&#34;&gt;PitsLamp&lt;/a&gt; on [Vimeo][4].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already trained twice with the forerunner 210 and it behaved as advertised, except for 1 thing. It does not calculate the calories I burn during the training. But after searching on the internet I found a solution for that. You have to hard reset the watch, because there is something wrong when you receive it from the factory, which makes that the user settings aren&amp;rsquo;t used during the training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hard reset procedure you need to perform is pressing the page/menu and lap/reset at the same time, and holding them until you see a prompt (about 3 seconds). This clears all data on the watch, it also clears your history so be aware that you upload the data first, before doing this reset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unboxing the Samsung Navibot VCR8855</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20101107_unboxing-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20101107_unboxing-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After moving from our apartment to a house we vey fast figured out that we had a lot more cleaning to do. Let that be one of our weak spots in the household. So we started thinking about a cleaning lady, but that turned out pretty expensive if you start looking at a longterm solution. So we decided we would buy a robot cleaner to at least vacuum the place every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started looking online for reviews and different types. It turns out there are only 2 different manufacturers of robot cleaners, the one we all know, iRobot with the roomba and Samsung with their navibots. There doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be a great difference between the different manufacturers at first sight. So why did we choose the navibot instead of a roomba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cat looses a lot of very fine hair so we needed a robot that could deal with that problem. After reading a lot of reviews and watching some YouTube videos about the different models, we decided that we needed the roomba pet series or the navibot VCR8855. So we went to the shop to actually see the robots. We didn&amp;rsquo;t find a roomba pet series in the shop, but we could examine the 555 series. After talking to the person responsible for the robot vacuum cleaners at vandenborre, the thing that made us decide is the difference in cleaning. The roombas wander around randomly while the navibot follows a structured path, to clean. So in our opinion the navibot cleans more thorough and more like we humans do. Although the navibot costs 499, euro vs 429 euro for the roomba, but with the navibot you get more accessories, but you&amp;rsquo;ll find that out in the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only time will tell if the navibot works for us, but that is the subject of another post. So now without further ado here is the unboxing video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/16573688&#34;&gt;Unboxing a Samsung Navibot VCR8855&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/pitslamp&#34;&gt;PitsLamp&lt;/a&gt; on [Vimeo][3].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony Nex-5, hands-on Review</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20101003_sony-nx-5-hands-on-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20101003_sony-nx-5-hands-on-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was given the samsung NX10 to test for 10 days, I was also handed a sony nex-5 a couple of weeks ago to play with it for one week. I&amp;rsquo;ve been postponing posting about this camera, because to be honest I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like it. The problem is not that I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the format, the quality or the technical parts of it. Actually I was very excited about those beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why did I not like the camera, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t intuitive. I tried to get over it and carried it with me for the whole week. The menu is not very logical, when I got the camera, I popped in a sd-card and wanted to format the card before taking pictures. Too bad it took me over 5 minutes to locate the format option in the menu. Because once you are in the menu, there are several submenu&amp;rsquo;s but the problem is that they are located vertically below each other and the camera stops scrolling for a little bit once you reach the end of the first menu. So you assume you reached the end of the menu and need to continue in another menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to that I was very annoyed by the startup time, it takes the camera 3-4 seconds to be able to take a picture. That&amp;rsquo;s too long for me. When I turn on a camera I want to be able to use it and not wait and loose the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most annoying thing was the fact that once you entered either photo or video mode, you could not review the results of the other mode without going to the unlogical menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So overall the camera is very nice, it would have been a great competitor compared to the samsung NX10, but sadly enough I didn&amp;rsquo;t take a lot of pictures because after the first day I got just very annoyed with it. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope sony fixes the each of use for their next release of this camera, it has a lot of potential but I would not recommend the camera to a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I think I deserve some recognition…</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20101001_i-think-i-deserve-some-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20101001_i-think-i-deserve-some-recognition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a quote from &amp;#8220;The Social Network&amp;#8221;, the movie I was invited to watch yesterday in a screening together with some other bloggers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The social network&amp;#8221; is the film about Marc Zuckerberg the founder of Facebook.com, a site I and probably you use every day. That for starters makes it very weird to watch the movie. I knew a bit about how the story of facebook goes and have to say, it stays very close to what happened in real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not that big of a film geek, that I know what the director made before and what the main actors are known for, but I can appreciate a good movie and have some attention for how the film is filmed. The first thing I noticed is a very distinctive style of filming and the great use of subtle light. That makes a movie already more interesting for me. Also the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m a geek, helps when the movie is about a geek creating the biggest social network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movie was very fastpaced and has two law suits from in the first years of facebook nicely intertwined with the story of how facebook grew from an idea to having 1 billion members. At moments it is a bit too fast to follow, so you&amp;rsquo;ll probably miss a lot of subtle humour. But at other moments the story seemed to drag along, with the biggest anticlimax the launch of thefacebook.com. Just a press on a button and that was it, not even a beer was cracked at that moment. A bit pity but if that&amp;rsquo;s the way it went, although just for the film&amp;rsquo;s sake I would have put it in, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although 2 hours is already pretty long for a movie, I found it disappointing that the biggest move facebook ever made, was not included in the film. I mean the film stopped at moving over to the UK universities and reaching there 1 billion members. I would have loved to see how it all grew and why they made the brightest and biggest move facebook could ever make, which was giving up being exclusive and going open to everybody, so that you and I now can be on facebook too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to figure out the feeling that I have after seeing the movie. I liked it, I liked it a lot. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a movie that will be a big hit, because of the niche of people that it will appeal to. I will definitely see it again, when it comes on tv or on dvd, if not only to figure out the feeling I&amp;rsquo;m left with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the trailer and thx &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adhese.com&#34; rel=&#34;contact met&#34; title=&#34;adhese.com&#34;&gt;Adhese&lt;/a&gt; for inviting me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samsung NX10, hands on review</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100721_samsung-nx10-hands-on-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100721_samsung-nx10-hands-on-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I had the opportunity to play with the Samsung NX10 camera. As said in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/20100620_samsung-nx10/&#34; title=&#34;Samsung NX10&#34;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt; I really liked the camera and that didn&amp;rsquo;t change during the 10 days I was allowed to use it. I even wanted to keep the camera with the 20mm pancake lens. Just because it is such an amazing small and convenient camera, it can go anywhere with you and it delivers great results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the NX10 to shoot some behind the scene material during a wedding with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bertstephani.com&#34;&gt;Bert Stephani&lt;/a&gt;. The photos are taken with the 20mm pancake lens and as jpeg in monochrome mode. The results are very good and I like the speed, the sharpness and the fast focus it has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791201689/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4141/4791201689_b7156075c9.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791202209/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4095/4791202209_1e48ba34f7.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791203085/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4119/4791203085_ab5304223e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also tried the NX10 during the &amp;#8220;dijlefeesten&amp;#8221; festival in my hometown and during some other low light conditions. The results are quite exceptional, the noise is very acceptable, that&amp;rsquo;s mainly because of the large sensor, it&amp;rsquo;s actually only a 1.5 crop factor. But not only the noise is very acceptable, the autofocus is also very good and fast even with the lights on stage flooding the frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791838302/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4141/4791838302_4cc8a52c73.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791208367/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4099/4791208367_978509c572.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791840000/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4143/4791840000_dbb4c00656.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can keep on talking about the technical stuff of this camera. Samsung had to make some compromises to keep the camera small but the experience with this camera is just great, I mean it just awesome to use, it&amp;rsquo;s small, fast, easy to use, but most of all it&amp;rsquo;s fun to use. Samsung keep up the good work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philips: “Obsessed with sound”</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100709_philips-obsessed-with-sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100709_philips-obsessed-with-sound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4775216821/&#34; title=&#34;[Event] Philips obsessed with sound by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4138/4775216821_0e4af4b7ff.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[Event] Philips obsessed with sound&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;/p?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last wednesday I was invited on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sound.philips.com/&#34; title=&#34;Obsessed with sound&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;Obsessed with sound event of Philips&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.galaxystudios.com/&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34; Title=&#34;Galaxy studios mol&#34;&gt;Galaxy studios&lt;/a&gt; in Mol. The purpose of this event is to submerge us in sound with one of their three heroes for the campagne, the producer of the soundtrack of batman begins, Geof Foster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bert Van Daele gave us a little history lesson about how Philips has and still is obsessed with sound since the beginning. Their main ideas since the beginning are that sound should be of best possible quality and sound should be available to everyone. Along those lines they created the first affordable radio in the 1920&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;#8220;het kappelke&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1940&amp;rsquo;s philips introduced the vinyl and created the philigraph. They kept on innovating in the 1950&amp;rsquo;s and they developed the kinetic tape. By the 1960&amp;rsquo;s Philips Hasselt developed the compact cassette and since then it became and still is the main music carrier. In 1968 they developed the cassette in the car. In the 70&amp;rsquo;s they developed the laser disc and they used the mpeg file format for video and audio. But in the 70&amp;rsquo;s the emphasis for Philips was more on video then on sound. In 1982 the audio cd was invented, it gave better quality and far more storage capacity. In the 90&amp;rsquo;s they started with DVD and SACD, where the DVD took of pretty well, the SACD was and still is a niche market. 2004 marked the date of the ambisound release and is another way to create surround sound without all the different speakers. And today we are here to see and hear the 360 sound speakers and systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4775870044/&#34; title=&#34;[Event] Philips obsessed with sound by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4099/4775870044_5217ae4e09.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;[Event] Philips obsessed with sound&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geof Foster was next up, he is the chief engineer for the batman begins soundtrack. He explained his workflow for making film music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all starts with spotting, which is basically putting some existing music against the different scenes. This process ends with a template to direct the composer. The second step is writing the music through the unique sound of the composer. The third part is scoring, this means choosing from the different sound generators like an orchestra. And the last part is a the actual mixing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geof gets involved mostly at the scoring stage, to record and create the sound, a big part of the scoring is choosing the layout and venue for the orchestra and the recording. He uses the batman begins soundtrack as an example. The recording is mostly done in separate parts. The very last thing is putting the music against the film and the sound of the movie itself. There is some more fine-tuning and listening if everything is in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Geoff also explained why the soundtrack is a little different from the music used in the film. Most music in the film is not always very interesting music wise, so they tweak it a bit for the OST&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4775212393/&#34; title=&#34;[Event] Philips obsessed with sound by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4080/4775212393_df6b244aaa.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;[Event] Philips obsessed with sound&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that Bert explained what the 360Sound is all about. It&amp;rsquo;s aimed at people that like good sound, but the speaker system has to be stylish. The 360Sound system has a front facing speaker and two speakers on the sides. The speakers on the side are aimed at bouncing of the walls to create a surround sound. The 360Sound is completely developed in Leuven, be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last product is the free floating tweeter, where they created a speaker which creates a full 360 degrees sound experience when the speaker is placed in the middle of the room. I like the idea, although the sound is not perfect, it is nice to have a device that sounds ok and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter where you are in the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philips also released a couple of iPhone/iPod dock speakers, they sound pretty awesome, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think they will take off until the one with the battery is released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the whole event took place in the Galaxy studios in Mol, one of the best recording studios in the world, we were entitled to a tour trough the complex, complete with the a movie from the late 80&amp;rsquo;s filmed during the building of the complex. It was quite impressive to see what they all did to make sure the best sound is recorded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check out the pictures at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/sets/72157624333488195/&#34; title=&#34;Philips obsessed with sound set at flickr&#34; rel=&#34;me&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked the event, I liked some of the products, but I&amp;rsquo;m not convinced they will take off with the high prices. I would have loved some more light to photograph the products. But thx [Talking Heads][4] and Philips for the invite and the Philips GoGear, which I will try to review a bitter later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.talkingheads.be&#34;&gt;http://www.talkingheads.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The iPad revolution</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100609_the-ipad-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100609_the-ipad-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;ve used my iPad for 12 days and I love it even more then I did the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love catching up with my RSS feeds, reading and replying to e-mails, writing blogposts and booking a hotel. The size of the screen makes it a great device for presenting pictures and watching series or movies streamed from my MBP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typing on the ipad is actually pretty good, you can&amp;rsquo;t use your regular typing position but typing with 6 fingers works very well. It&amp;rsquo;s just an awesome device to use all the time and everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are a few small things that annoy me. First of all Apple should have included some way to prop up the iPad when resting it in your lap or putting it on the table to type with 2 hands. Now I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a way to elevate it a bit and most of the time I&amp;rsquo;m putting my wallet under it, because that&amp;rsquo;s the perfect height and doesn&amp;rsquo;t slip. But at the moment I did not find any great case yet. I would love the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dodocase.com&#34;&gt;DODO case&lt;/a&gt; but they are backordered for 4 to 6 weeks and they are missing a nice height for watching movies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another annoying thing is that at the moment there is no Twitter client that I like and definitely no app that satisfies my needs for google reader, but off course there&amp;rsquo;s an app for that at least over time there will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most annoying thing is taking it out of your bag in Belgium. once you take it out to usef it, there&amp;rsquo;s always somebody who starts saying that there are better things to use, you can&amp;rsquo;t do this or that,&amp;#8230; Basically I like my iPad, it serves the purpose where I bought it for, so just let me use it and don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m taking it out to brag, I just want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m going to stop this blogpost so I can watch [chase jarvis live][2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chasejarvis.com/live&#34;&gt;http://www.chasejarvis.com/live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of #s3dTV event</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100602_review-of-s3dtv-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100602_review-of-s3dtv-event/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4657447871/&#34; title=&#34;[event] Samsung 3D TV by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4013/4657447871_4b8eb83963.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[event] Samsung 3D TV&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I did some live blogging during the presentation, but last night and today I had some time to think about the evening and all the stuff we&amp;rsquo;ve seen. My initial thoughts are, the organisation could have been a bit better. Although the venue was very fine, the little food I got my hands on was good and the goodie bags were awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4657467635/&#34; title=&#34;[event] Samsung 3D TV by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4045/4657467635_1ccec7c748.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[event] Samsung 3D TV&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentations could have been less confusing and the quiz afterwards should have been organized better. It was a very nice way of letting us vote, but apparently some of the remotes didn&amp;rsquo;t work, which off course manipulated the results quite a bit. Not that I was harmed by that, I just don&amp;rsquo;t know enough info about movies. Very important I think there should have been a round for questions after every presentation, because a lot of people had questions about the TV&amp;rsquo;s that could have been interesting for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4658046626/&#34; title=&#34;[event] Samsung 3D TV by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1297/4658046626_f92658a20b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[event] Samsung 3D TV&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But on the 3D itself now. I&amp;rsquo;m still not convinced about the whole concept of 3D. I don&amp;rsquo;t really like watching a movie in 3D, first of all, it still feels very unreal. The biggest drawback is that in order to experience 3D TV, you still need to wear a pair of glasses, who are btw very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine following situation: you&amp;rsquo;re coming home after a day of work, you eat something, decide to watch some relaxing television, but wait&amp;#8230;, where did I leave the glasses, I mean I&amp;rsquo;m already having trouble locating the remote control of the TV. Let&amp;rsquo;s say I found them, apparently our cat decided that the glasses were to play with and has left some scratches and bite marks all over it. Well, still not really a problem, let&amp;rsquo;s just try them on, oh wait, they are not charged anymore, because i forgot to put them in the USB charger. By now my relax evening of watching TV has been ruined already. So I decide to ditch the glasses, turn off the TV and get behind the computer to get some more work done. Great&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is fictional, for the moment, but at a certain point this could turn into reality. I don&amp;rsquo;t want that kind of reality. Give me a 2D screen, which I turn on, look for the remote for about a minute and further on I can watch the 50th rerun of &amp;#8220;Allo, Allo&amp;#8221; or something. I find it a pretty stupid concept to try to mimic 3D in film or a serie, because you can&amp;rsquo;t interact with the world that&amp;rsquo;s living around you. So in that perspective I think gaming in 3D has a future, yesterday I played a bit with avatar in 3D and I very much liked it. Because you are in the 3D environment you can better experience the game and interact with it. Although I still think that for a game to be using 3D to the fullest you really need to be in the middle of the game terrain, like it was promised with Virtual Reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all I had a fun evening, met some nice people, saw the regular crowd again and as usual shot some photos (find more in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/sets/72157624176827836/&#34; title=&#34;Set, Samsung s3dTV&#34;&gt;set&lt;/a&gt;). But I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone of the people at the event will buy a television that starts at 1800 euro with only 2 glasses and without a lot of quality content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>