<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robot Cleaner on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/robot-cleaner/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robot Cleaner on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/robot-cleaner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of the Samsung Navibot VCR8855</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110127_review-of-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110127_review-of-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After more than 2 months using the Navibot, I want to give you a review. Let me say, we&amp;rsquo;re pretty pleased with the Robot vacuum cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it&amp;rsquo;s not a total solution for cleaning, it does a very good job keeping the house clean, when you set it on a daily routine. It takes a structured path, which takes it through the most part of the room. During it&amp;rsquo;s path, it tries to cover the whole area, but misses some spots. Luckily it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take the same path everyday and does the missed spots the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a week we empty the container containing the dust and hairs,. So it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require a lot of maintanance but whenever you forget about putting away all toys for the cat or the floorcloths, we use as doormats, something is bound to get stuck in the rotating brushes. Then the robot stops and starts beeping, until you fix the problem, that&amp;rsquo;s annoying and drives our cat crazy when we aren&amp;rsquo;t at home. But apart from that, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get trapped under furniture, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t wrecks anything around the home. It only bumps into the furniture that has legs that are smaller than 5cm because it is in the blind spot of the sensors. Even when it does bump into your furniture, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really damages it, because of the rubber bumpers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only very annoying thing about the robot is whenever you use the guards, it gets confused because the beam of the guard spreads wider then you intend and that leaves areas around the guard without cleaning. Our robot also had a little defect, which broke the system that makes the back brush rotate and we had to send it in for repair. Since then it drives around and cleans the whole area very good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a decent robot vacuum cleaner, then this is definitely what you need. It does a really good job keeping the house clean, without you lifting a finger, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not perfect but it&amp;rsquo;s a great aid. For us it is a great tool and definitely cheaper than paying a cleaning lady. So yes, it&amp;rsquo;s an expensive buy, but it will pay off after a while, because maintenance is not expensive at all. Even after 2 months we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to change any of the brushes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unboxing the Samsung Navibot VCR8855</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20101107_unboxing-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20101107_unboxing-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After moving from our apartment to a house we vey fast figured out that we had a lot more cleaning to do. Let that be one of our weak spots in the household. So we started thinking about a cleaning lady, but that turned out pretty expensive if you start looking at a longterm solution. So we decided we would buy a robot cleaner to at least vacuum the place every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started looking online for reviews and different types. It turns out there are only 2 different manufacturers of robot cleaners, the one we all know, iRobot with the roomba and Samsung with their navibots. There doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be a great difference between the different manufacturers at first sight. So why did we choose the navibot instead of a roomba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cat looses a lot of very fine hair so we needed a robot that could deal with that problem. After reading a lot of reviews and watching some YouTube videos about the different models, we decided that we needed the roomba pet series or the navibot VCR8855. So we went to the shop to actually see the robots. We didn&amp;rsquo;t find a roomba pet series in the shop, but we could examine the 555 series. After talking to the person responsible for the robot vacuum cleaners at vandenborre, the thing that made us decide is the difference in cleaning. The roombas wander around randomly while the navibot follows a structured path, to clean. So in our opinion the navibot cleans more thorough and more like we humans do. Although the navibot costs 499, euro vs 429 euro for the roomba, but with the navibot you get more accessories, but you&amp;rsquo;ll find that out in the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only time will tell if the navibot works for us, but that is the subject of another post. So now without further ado here is the unboxing video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/16573688&#34;&gt;Unboxing a Samsung Navibot VCR8855&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/pitslamp&#34;&gt;PitsLamp&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>