<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nex 5n on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/nex-5n/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nex 5n on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/nex-5n/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>[review] Sony nex-5n</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20120307_review-sony-nex-5n/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20120307_review-sony-nex-5n/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6815151696/&#34; title=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Sunrise in the mist by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7056/6815151696_ddc8e7af7d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;332&#34; alt=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Sunrise in the mist&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sony is really good at letting me test their new cameras. A little while ago I had the chance to test the Sony nex-5n, the successor of the nex-5. I had the pleasure of photographing with the nex-5, which I reviewed over &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/20101003_sony-nx-5-hands-on-review/&#34; title=&#34;Sony Nex-5, hands-on Review&#34; rel=&#34;me&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. As I said then, I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the menus, the startup time, &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5n is a whole different deal, in fact it&amp;rsquo;s a great camera. Sony really listened to their users, they did a real good job cleaning up the menu-interface. It feels snappy, intuitive and very logical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6815149410/&#34; title=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] NOTP by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7038/6815149410_1aaa5d034e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] NOTP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the photos is great, it can match the quality of my 5d MK II, which is about 1500 euro more expensive. The photo above is a shot of a concert at 3200 iso, with the standard jpg b/w conversion on it. There is almost no noise and the image is pretty sharp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6961267217/&#34; title=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Spa-Francorchamps by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7204/6961267217_844a8bc86d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;332&#34; alt=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Spa-Francorchamps&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other concern about the nex-5 was the that the camera was pretty slow, well the 5n is definitely not slow. It has a fast autofocus, pretty short start up time, but when you can capture a race-car in full focus on a track, I can only say that it&amp;rsquo;s really fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6815150124/&#34; title=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Me by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7208/6815150124_ebb4faab7d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;332&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Me&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as with every camera, there are a couple of drawbacks, the first being that you don&amp;rsquo;t have a viewfinder, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty annoying when photographing in bright light. Sony kinda solved this problem by adding a swiveling screen, a very sturdy one I have to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there is the fact that the flash is external, an sich not a real problem, except sony doens&amp;rsquo;t like standard hotshoes. They didn&amp;rsquo;t even include the typical sony hotshoe, so the only way you can use a flash is by using the included small flash, a flash I don&amp;rsquo;t like. It&amp;rsquo;s small, there are almost no way to control it and it feels pretty filmsy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most annoying thing, but that&amp;rsquo;s something I have found in all Sony cameras is the way, you can review your photos and videos on it. I can imagine some people find it very good, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the menu to view everything I have on my card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the few things I didn&amp;rsquo;t like that much, the nex-5n is a very decent camera. Even so good that my girlfriend and I are actually considering buying one, how&amp;rsquo;s that for a reference. I test a lot of mirrorless cameras and this is the first I really think is up to par with all DSLR&amp;rsquo;s in the same or even a bit higher price range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thx to my girlfriend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saravdv.be&#34; title=&#34;There are no endings, only new beginnings&#34; rel=&#34;contact, friend&#34;&gt;Saravdv&lt;/a&gt; for taking most of the pictures.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>