<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>[review] Backblaze, cloud backup</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20130109_review-backblaze-cloud-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20130109_review-backblaze-cloud-backup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/logo_backblaze.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/logo_backblaze.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Backblaze&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;52&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-271&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started using computers, I have had a mixed relation with backups. They are too much hassle to deal with, they fail, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough space. But since the internet connections are able to handle all data I produce now, I decided to start using cloud backup. I&amp;rsquo;v chosen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com&#34; title=&#34;Online Backup &amp;#038; Data Backup Software&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Backblaze cloud backup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had and still have a fully installed and running local backup system. But it took me a while to figure out an easy way to have a offsite backup for my photography. The problem is that having an off site backup used to be a lot of work, I tried several ways, but never found a way that worked reliably and wasn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only easy way, was and still is by uploading everything, but the problem in Belgium was that there were up and download limits set by the providers. Even today on the &amp;#8220;unlimited&amp;#8221; packages there still is a kind of restriction, it is around 500 gb to 1TB a month depending on the area you live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-backblaze&#34;&gt;Why Backblaze?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After extensively researching the different solutions, I decide to go with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com&#34; title=&#34;Online Backup &amp;#038; Data Backup Software&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;, because of the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup external drives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throttle upload speed of your data when needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship backup drives worldwide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only 4$ a month if you choose the 2 year plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlimited backup space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I found, there are no other services that offer all these options for that money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-does-it-work&#34;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works great, after subscribing and paying with your credit card, you download and install the program for your OS. Backblaze will start to upload data from your internal drives. If you want to add more drives, just select it in the preferences pane. If you have upload limits, you can choose to throttle the speed and Blackblaze gives you an estimate how much it will upload during a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few figures to give you an idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.2 TB data backed up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial backup took 3.5 months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored main OS X data once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored 35 GB in a zip-file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;is-it-good&#34;&gt;Is it good?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it took almost 4 months of backing up, it was no hassle, Backblaze just worked. Restoring was just a matter of selecting the files I wanted, waiting for the zip to be generated and then downloading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not all good, the restore process sucks. You&amp;rsquo;ll get all your files back, but it&amp;rsquo;s up to you to put them all back where they belong. That&amp;rsquo;s no fun, let me tell you. You have to deal with permissions, finding the correct folder and so on. Another annoyance, is the fact that after the restore, my secondary internal drive was no longer recognized as being the same drive, so it had to be backed up again, like the replaced primary drive. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backblaze is a great solution for an off site backup, but it takes a while to get all your data backed up, my suggestion let me send you guys a drive with my data for an extra cost, like crashplan does. When you have to restore, it&amp;rsquo;s all manual labour. I would suggest that they implement some sort of restore program that does most of the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the remarks I have, I&amp;rsquo;m a satisfied &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com&#34; title=&#34;Online Backup &amp;#038; Data Backup Software&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Backblaze cloud backup&lt;/a&gt; user and would recommend it to everybody&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wasn’t forced to write this blogpost, everything in here is my own view, the content wasn’t reviewed by any departement of the brands mentioned in here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[review] Kingston 3K hyperX SSD</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20121020_review-kingston-3k-hyperx-ssd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20121020_review-kingston-3k-hyperx-ssd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: after 5 months this Kingston 3K hyperX SSD completely died on me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/hyperx.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/hyperx.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kingston 3K HyperX SSD&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-267&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of june, my girflfriend (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saravdv.be&#34; rel=&#34;friend muse&#34; title=&#34;Saravdv: there are no endings, only new beginnings&#34;&gt;SaraVdV&lt;/a&gt;) got a mail from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kingston.com&#34; title=&#34;Kingston Technology&#34; rel=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Kingston&lt;/a&gt; if she and I wanted to test a new SSD drive from Kingston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some mailing back and forth, because Sara and I both work on mac&amp;rsquo;s, Kingston send us both a 256GB HyperX 3K SSD drive. It comes in a nice package, with an external usb enclosure and it&amp;rsquo;s own screwdriver. Which is always very handy. The drives we received were 2.5&amp;#8243; drives, but included in the package you buy, there&amp;rsquo;s also a 3.5&amp;#8243; bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it would be easier from me to put the drive in the MacBook pro 15&amp;#8243; begin 2009 I have, than to put it in an iMac. I started with that computer, the drive is as easy to install as any drive. However when I booted the mac and started installing OS X I ran into some problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first the install of OS X stalled a couple of times, when I finally managed to install it correctly, I had a 25 sec spinning beachball every 2 minutes. However, because we had review drives, I contacted Kingston directly and started to work out the problem with Mario, on of the engineers at Kingston who developed the drive. Turns out that there is an incompatibility between the nvidia SATA I controller in the MacBook 5.1 and the driver for SATA II or III SSD&amp;rsquo;s in OS X leopard or later. This makes that every time there is a lot of writing activity to the disk that the controller locks the OS for a while untill the buffers are cleared. So I ended up restoring this MacBook to it&amp;rsquo;s original config. This is not a fault of the kingston drive but an Apple problem, because I also experienced the same behaviour with another brand of SSD&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my debacle with the drive in the Macbook 5.1, I also installed the drive in Sara&amp;rsquo;s iMac which is not too big of a hassle if you follow all the guides online for replacing a drive in an iMac. I have not had any problems with installing the drive and reinstalling OS X, nor has Sara experienced any problems since the drive was installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July I purchased myself a new 13&amp;#8243; MacBook pro and installed the HyperX SSD in that computer. No problems, everything installs and works perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performance wise, everything seems a lot quicker on the iMac of Sara, boot times improved a lot. Every program launches faster and the drive behaves very well under pressure. We didn&amp;rsquo;t do any graphs or charts, because in the end it all comes down to how you preceive the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the MacBook 13&amp;#8243; I did some testing. Without SSD it cold booted in 34 seconds, after install of the SSD it cold boots in 8secs. That&amp;rsquo;s just amazing. It feels more instant now then waking my iPad first generation from sleep. Programs are launching very fast, lightroom which is the most important program for me, launches in less then 3 seconds in grid view. It all feels very snappy and instant. I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a beachball in months. Reboots are only necessary for updates from the OS. It just works and feels fast. It does what I expected an SSD to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nicest surprise is that we may keep the drives, so I got a nice upgrade for my new MacBook thanks to Kingston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t forced to write this blogpost, everything in here is my own view, the content wasn&amp;rsquo;t reviewed by any departement of the brands mentioned in here. I did however receive a compensation for this post. So decide for yourself how much value you want to attribute to this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Review] Logitech F540</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20120307_review-logitech-f540/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20120307_review-logitech-f540/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6796342627/&#34; title=&#34;[Samsung nx200] Logitech F540 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7168/6796342627_8e4fea1b01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[Samsung nx200] Logitech F540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing the xbox late at night, while my girlfriend is asleep, isn&amp;rsquo;t possible. So I asked Logitech if I could test out the Logitech F540 wireless headphones for game consoles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days later I had the headphones. After unpacking the rather neatly put together box, it was very easy hooking it up to the Xbox. You basically plugg 2 wires into the basestation. The power and the audio cable. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t be easier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After turning on the headphones and pushing the sync button on both the station and the headphones, all was set. I played several hours while wearing the headset and was very pleased with the battery life, about 10 play hours. The sound quality for me was great too, although I&amp;rsquo;m not really a sound guy, but heck it was decent enough to hear the rain fall in Oblivion which for me is all I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t really use the microphone in game, but it&amp;rsquo;s pleasing to hear yourself through the headphones when the mic is on, so you don&amp;rsquo;t scream when talking. I did try it once and it seemed to work decent enough, but I can&amp;rsquo;t really tell because none of the other players in the game bothered to talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most headphones are quite hard to wear after a while, because my ear gets pinched, but the F540 has cups that go all around your ear, not on your ear which is very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only big problem I had and what for me is kinda of a deal breaker, is that fact that I got loads of interference after a while. Especially when the Xbox was online over the wifi signal, I tried all solutions found on the web, but none really helped, except putting the transmitter at a 45 degrees angle, but that is not very handy when you need somebody to hold the transmitter while you are playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So overall, I like the headset a lot, but there are 2 things I didn&amp;rsquo;t like, one is that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t use digital audio on it, which is very annoying because our tv only has a headphones and digital out connection and the headphones is never surround and the second one was the interference I got from other devices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[review] Sony nex-5n</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20120307_review-sony-nex-5n/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20120307_review-sony-nex-5n/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6815151696/&#34; title=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Sunrise in the mist by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7056/6815151696_ddc8e7af7d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;332&#34; alt=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Sunrise in the mist&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sony is really good at letting me test their new cameras. A little while ago I had the chance to test the Sony nex-5n, the successor of the nex-5. I had the pleasure of photographing with the nex-5, which I reviewed over &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/20101003_sony-nx-5-hands-on-review/&#34; title=&#34;Sony Nex-5, hands-on Review&#34; rel=&#34;me&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. As I said then, I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the menus, the startup time, &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5n is a whole different deal, in fact it&amp;rsquo;s a great camera. Sony really listened to their users, they did a real good job cleaning up the menu-interface. It feels snappy, intuitive and very logical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6815149410/&#34; title=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] NOTP by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7038/6815149410_1aaa5d034e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] NOTP&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the photos is great, it can match the quality of my 5d MK II, which is about 1500 euro more expensive. The photo above is a shot of a concert at 3200 iso, with the standard jpg b/w conversion on it. There is almost no noise and the image is pretty sharp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6961267217/&#34; title=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Spa-Francorchamps by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7204/6961267217_844a8bc86d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;332&#34; alt=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Spa-Francorchamps&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other concern about the nex-5 was the that the camera was pretty slow, well the 5n is definitely not slow. It has a fast autofocus, pretty short start up time, but when you can capture a race-car in full focus on a track, I can only say that it&amp;rsquo;s really fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6815150124/&#34; title=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Me by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7208/6815150124_ebb4faab7d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;332&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;[Sony nex-5n] Me&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as with every camera, there are a couple of drawbacks, the first being that you don&amp;rsquo;t have a viewfinder, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty annoying when photographing in bright light. Sony kinda solved this problem by adding a swiveling screen, a very sturdy one I have to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there is the fact that the flash is external, an sich not a real problem, except sony doens&amp;rsquo;t like standard hotshoes. They didn&amp;rsquo;t even include the typical sony hotshoe, so the only way you can use a flash is by using the included small flash, a flash I don&amp;rsquo;t like. It&amp;rsquo;s small, there are almost no way to control it and it feels pretty filmsy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most annoying thing, but that&amp;rsquo;s something I have found in all Sony cameras is the way, you can review your photos and videos on it. I can imagine some people find it very good, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go through the menu to view everything I have on my card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the few things I didn&amp;rsquo;t like that much, the nex-5n is a very decent camera. Even so good that my girlfriend and I are actually considering buying one, how&amp;rsquo;s that for a reference. I test a lot of mirrorless cameras and this is the first I really think is up to par with all DSLR&amp;rsquo;s in the same or even a bit higher price range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thx to my girlfriend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saravdv.be&#34; title=&#34;There are no endings, only new beginnings&#34; rel=&#34;contact, friend&#34;&gt;Saravdv&lt;/a&gt; for taking most of the pictures.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Review] Samsung NX200</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20120206_review-samsung-nx200/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20120206_review-samsung-nx200/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://500px.com/photo/4714308&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pcdn.500px.net/4714308/cc7bd653dc8402e2871aee39975ca5463fa1f52b/4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Samsung nx200] Long exposures by Filip Bunkens (Pitslamp)) on 500px.com&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a professional photographer, I get to test new cameras when they are released. That&amp;rsquo;s how I got my hands on a Samsung NX200 for a couple of months now. This review is going to from a professional viewpoint, if you want a less technical review check out my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pitslamp.com/blog/20120131_samsung_nx200&#34; title=&#34;Samsung NX200 review | PitsLamp&#34;&gt;PitsLamp blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nx200 is a mirror less camera system, with some pretty decent lenses. I&amp;rsquo;ll list the pro and cons of the camera and will explain some a bit lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pro&#34;&gt;Pro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretty high fps in RAW (4) even higher in JPEG (7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nice intuitive interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hot shoe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very accessible buttons on the right locations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good quality AMOLED display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 MP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good form factor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;con&#34;&gt;Con&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lot&amp;rsquo;s of noise above ISO 800&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slow startup time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No viewfinder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No swiveling display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the very short version of my likes and dislikes of the Samsung NX200. So now let me get into that in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;screen&#34;&gt;Screen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the screen is great, even in harsh sunlight. However, because of no viewfinder and no swiveling screen, it&amp;rsquo;s not always very easy to compose a shot. You are limited to how you can look at the screen. This means no shots low by the ground, or high above your head, because composing is not possible if you don&amp;rsquo;t see the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ease-of-use&#34;&gt;Ease of use&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samsung always had a pretty good idea how to make a camera easy to use. The menu is clear, easy, logical. All the buttons are located very conveniently, at least for me they are. It&amp;rsquo;s a joy to use this camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However how hard Samsung keeps on trying to have me use the i-Function button on the lens, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care for it. It&amp;rsquo;s is one of their selling points since the nx100, it was made after the older rangefinder cameras where you could set almost everything on the lens. But where Samsung got it wrong for me, is that the button is never in the same place on the lenses. Also the first you use the button it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really react directly. Also the ring on the lens you can use to change the settings, is stepless, but the interface on the screen has steps, that&amp;rsquo;s confusing. So I prefer to use the buttons on top and on the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quality-and-speed&#34;&gt;Quality and speed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A slow startup speed, makes that you better don&amp;rsquo;t use the battery saving feature, if you want to photograph your kids, make sure you keep it on all the time. However once started, the speed is very good, a very decent fps even in RAW. On the other hand, once you want to look at the photos, it can take quite some time before the RAW&amp;rsquo;s are processed. So speed overall is not good enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6796342627/&#34; title=&#34;[Samsung nx200] Logitech F540 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7168/6796342627_8e4fea1b01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[Samsung nx200] Logitech F540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 20MP on the camera, the photos are of good quality, large, nice to look at in 100%. The camera is excellent for studio work in tight spaces, I did love it for product shots, especially with the 60mm macro lens. The hot shoe makes it possible to use radio triggers which again is awesome for studio shoots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a very big drawback, as with the first DSLR&amp;rsquo;s the camera, absolutely doesn&amp;rsquo;t perform well in low light conditions. For me in color the photos until 800 iso are acceptable, in b/w you can go up till 1600 but after that you&amp;rsquo;re out of luck. Too much noise, especially color noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have mixed feelings about this camera. I do like the interface, but I don&amp;rsquo;t like the quality of the photos. So if you are looking for a small, interchangeable camera with most use being during the day or in studio settings, definitely go for it. If you are looking for an allround camera, don&amp;rsquo;t go for this one, there are better alternatives out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logitech Magic</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110930_logitech-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110930_logitech-magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I got invited to the logitech magic event in Belgium together with some other bloggers. We rode out to Arquennes about 30 minutes from Brussels in Henegouwen. On arrival we were greeted with a glass of champagne and a short explanation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/wim_wauters&#34; title=&#34;Wim Wauters, on Twitter&#34; rel=&#34;contact met&#34;&gt;@wimwauters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images&#34; width=&#34;455&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-178&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got a tour around all the different products and in the mean time, there was a contest organized. I saw some nice products, but the most are not suited for me, because I have a fondness of the keyboards and mice/trackpads from Apple. The keys are just nicer from apple then any other keyboard I have used. However the accessoires for the ipad were very interesting, sadly enough the most interesting ones, like the keyboard cover are not suited for my iPad 1. But I can understand why a company developing products for Apple lines, are developing for the current versions alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contest had a pretty interesting take, because Logitech and Hill and Knowlton anticipated that we would cheat.  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:-)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;So they had a guess question included, which was how many tweets with the logitechmagic tag would be posted between 20 and 22h during the evening. As everybody was working together on finding the answers to the questions this actually was the only relevant question to receive the prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The range of prices was impressive, there was a surround system with a value of 350 euro to mice of 30 euro. But at least everybody got a price. I managed to get a set of Logitech 600vi in-ear phones. I&amp;rsquo;m currently testing them and I have to say the are amazingly great. These earphones are from the ultimate ear line, which is the same product line where a lot of professional musician are wearing headphones from during their concerts. The pair Sara and I got have a price value of 109 euro, which for me is very steep. That price means I would have never bought them myself, because I have a very bad track record with headphones. They tend to lay around and get tangled, ripped, get loose connections and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These seem very nicely and sturdy designed, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how they handle my abuse in the long run. The sound experience is quite impressive. I get a wide range of tones without any distortion or scrambling. The nice part is that there is a whole range of foam and plastic tips so you can choose the ones that fit your ear very nicely. I have a rather small ear channel and most tips don&amp;rsquo;t fit my ears, but the ones with the logitech ear phones actually fit my ear quite comfortable. I&amp;rsquo;m wearing them already several hours in a row, without getting any problems with having them falling out of my ear or without any discomfort. So my initial experience with these in-ear phones is very positive. So thanks a lot Logitech for a quite expensive goodie of good quality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony Nex-5, hands-on Review</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20101003_sony-nx-5-hands-on-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20101003_sony-nx-5-hands-on-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was given the samsung NX10 to test for 10 days, I was also handed a sony nex-5 a couple of weeks ago to play with it for one week. I&amp;rsquo;ve been postponing posting about this camera, because to be honest I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like it. The problem is not that I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the format, the quality or the technical parts of it. Actually I was very excited about those beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why did I not like the camera, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t intuitive. I tried to get over it and carried it with me for the whole week. The menu is not very logical, when I got the camera, I popped in a sd-card and wanted to format the card before taking pictures. Too bad it took me over 5 minutes to locate the format option in the menu. Because once you are in the menu, there are several submenu&amp;rsquo;s but the problem is that they are located vertically below each other and the camera stops scrolling for a little bit once you reach the end of the first menu. So you assume you reached the end of the menu and need to continue in another menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to that I was very annoyed by the startup time, it takes the camera 3-4 seconds to be able to take a picture. That&amp;rsquo;s too long for me. When I turn on a camera I want to be able to use it and not wait and loose the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most annoying thing was the fact that once you entered either photo or video mode, you could not review the results of the other mode without going to the unlogical menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So overall the camera is very nice, it would have been a great competitor compared to the samsung NX10, but sadly enough I didn&amp;rsquo;t take a lot of pictures because after the first day I got just very annoyed with it. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope sony fixes the each of use for their next release of this camera, it has a lot of potential but I would not recommend the camera to a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samsung NX10, hands on review</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100721_samsung-nx10-hands-on-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100721_samsung-nx10-hands-on-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I had the opportunity to play with the Samsung NX10 camera. As said in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/20100620_samsung-nx10/&#34; title=&#34;Samsung NX10&#34;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt; I really liked the camera and that didn&amp;rsquo;t change during the 10 days I was allowed to use it. I even wanted to keep the camera with the 20mm pancake lens. Just because it is such an amazing small and convenient camera, it can go anywhere with you and it delivers great results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the NX10 to shoot some behind the scene material during a wedding with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bertstephani.com&#34;&gt;Bert Stephani&lt;/a&gt;. The photos are taken with the 20mm pancake lens and as jpeg in monochrome mode. The results are very good and I like the speed, the sharpness and the fast focus it has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791201689/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4141/4791201689_b7156075c9.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791202209/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4095/4791202209_1e48ba34f7.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791203085/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4119/4791203085_ab5304223e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also tried the NX10 during the &amp;#8220;dijlefeesten&amp;#8221; festival in my hometown and during some other low light conditions. The results are quite exceptional, the noise is very acceptable, that&amp;rsquo;s mainly because of the large sensor, it&amp;rsquo;s actually only a 1.5 crop factor. But not only the noise is very acceptable, the autofocus is also very good and fast even with the lights on stage flooding the frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791838302/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4141/4791838302_4cc8a52c73.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791208367/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4099/4791208367_978509c572.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791840000/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4143/4791840000_dbb4c00656.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can keep on talking about the technical stuff of this camera. Samsung had to make some compromises to keep the camera small but the experience with this camera is just great, I mean it just awesome to use, it&amp;rsquo;s small, fast, easy to use, but most of all it&amp;rsquo;s fun to use. Samsung keep up the good work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The iPad revolution</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100609_the-ipad-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100609_the-ipad-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;ve used my iPad for 12 days and I love it even more then I did the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love catching up with my RSS feeds, reading and replying to e-mails, writing blogposts and booking a hotel. The size of the screen makes it a great device for presenting pictures and watching series or movies streamed from my MBP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typing on the ipad is actually pretty good, you can&amp;rsquo;t use your regular typing position but typing with 6 fingers works very well. It&amp;rsquo;s just an awesome device to use all the time and everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are a few small things that annoy me. First of all Apple should have included some way to prop up the iPad when resting it in your lap or putting it on the table to type with 2 hands. Now I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a way to elevate it a bit and most of the time I&amp;rsquo;m putting my wallet under it, because that&amp;rsquo;s the perfect height and doesn&amp;rsquo;t slip. But at the moment I did not find any great case yet. I would love the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dodocase.com&#34;&gt;DODO case&lt;/a&gt; but they are backordered for 4 to 6 weeks and they are missing a nice height for watching movies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another annoying thing is that at the moment there is no Twitter client that I like and definitely no app that satisfies my needs for google reader, but off course there&amp;rsquo;s an app for that at least over time there will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most annoying thing is taking it out of your bag in Belgium. once you take it out to usef it, there&amp;rsquo;s always somebody who starts saying that there are better things to use, you can&amp;rsquo;t do this or that,&amp;#8230; Basically I like my iPad, it serves the purpose where I bought it for, so just let me use it and don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m taking it out to brag, I just want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m going to stop this blogpost so I can watch &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chasejarvis.com/live&#34;&gt;chase jarvis live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>