<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ceo on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/ceo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ceo on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/ceo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of an era: Steve Jobs</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110825_the-end-of-an-era-steve-jobs-steps-down-as-ceo-of-apple-inc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110825_the-end-of-an-era-steve-jobs-steps-down-as-ceo-of-apple-inc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/steve-jobs1.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/steve-jobs1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;steve-jobs1&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; height=&#34;287&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-170&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a huge Apple fanboy, it&amp;rsquo;s a very sad day for me. Steve Jobs just announced his resignation as a CEO of Apple inc. Below you find the most significant part from his resignation letter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always said if there ever came a day when I could no longer meet my duties and expectations as Apple’s CEO, I would be the first to let you know. Unfortunately, that day has come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steve Jobs &amp;#8211; Resignation Letter august 24, 2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that Steve&amp;rsquo;s health was on a bad streak, starting with his pancreas cancer in 2006, his liver transplant in 2009 and the indefinite leave of absence due to health issues. Every keynote we saw a sleeker and sleeker Steve at this rate, he would be no more than a skeleton by the release of the iPhone 6. But I hoped that Steve would recover and kick some more butt in the years to come. Sadly that won&amp;rsquo;t be true anymore. Let&amp;rsquo;s just hope, that Steve can now focus on his health a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I say, the end of an era? A look at his track record, which reads like a good novel and is a string of successes, says it all. The story starts in 1976 with the release of the Apple I, a computer built in a garage by 2 very young guys, dreaming that one day they could earn a profit from it. Little would they know that was the beginning of a dream come true. Although Wozniak left Apple and Jobs was fired in the nineties and hired back afterwards, in which time he founded, build and make Pixar huge. Now Apple not only has produced great products, but it has also become the biggest company in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Jobs now resigning as CEO I still believe in Apple and they will keep on producing great products, but there won&amp;rsquo;t be anymore iconic black turtle necks, no more casual &amp;#8220;There&amp;rsquo;s one more thing&amp;#8221; to drop a bomb on a market. I fear that the cult of mac, will no longer exist, it has lost it leader. Apple will probably become a dull company that still makes great products, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t have me sitting in suspense during a keynote what they will announce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off course Jobs is not without fault, I&amp;rsquo;m the first to admit it, but he is kind of a hero for me. Creating a company from scratch and making it this big, but still maintaining the suspense when announcing something new. There is no other company that I know of where one man had such an impact on the development, announcement and sales of a product that nobody needed before it was announced. It also takes a great man, to resign due to health reasons from the company you built from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that one day, I can look back at my life and say I made an impact, as did Steve Jobs, my personal hero business wise. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t has to be as significant as Steve&amp;rsquo;s impact, but I would like to know that I have done well according to my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So hereby I salute you, Steve, you are a great man and leader. Take care.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>