<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paris on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/paris/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paris on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/paris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>road trip to Paris</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100528_road-trip-to-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100528_road-trip-to-paris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had some crazy ideas before and I&amp;rsquo;ve build quite a reputation of opening shops of my favourite brands and queueing for gadgets. When, last January I saw Steve jobs unveil the iPad, I was sold. I also knew I would be queueing for it when it became available in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today was the day of the official release for the iPad In France. in the past days I have been researching a lot about the release on the internet. Well actually I was researching it with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pietervanimpe.com&#34; rel=&#34;friend collegue met&#34; title=&#34;Pieter Van Impe&#34;&gt;Pieter&lt;/a&gt;, we first thought of going to the fnac in Lille. It turned we could be left without an iPad to buy, so we decided to go to Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight at midnight we left for Paris accompanied by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saravdv.be&#34;&gt;Sara&lt;/a&gt; and [Davy][2]. We arrived at 3h30 and found a parking spot surprisingly easy just around the corner of the apple store. There were already 6 people in front of us, but at least we knew we would have an iPad and so the waiting began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the hour got closer, Pieter and I were wondering about which one we would get, while Sara was deciding if she would get one. Unfortunately we didn&amp;rsquo;t have all the time waiting to decide because the press found out that there were some crazy Belgians in the queue. Most of them wanted to talk to us. We gave some interviews and were asked by a production crew of Apple to be followed while and after buying the iPad. We even got an iTunes gift certificate of 15€ out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t found all the links to the videos and articles yet but I&amp;rsquo;ll add them once I&amp;rsquo;ve found them.&amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is typed on the iPad and I found it pretty pleasing to type a small blogpost like this one in the WP app. After playing with it for the last hour I&amp;rsquo;m even more convinced that I wanted this device. I&amp;rsquo;ll write a review and some app recommendations later aft i used it for an extended time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davybuntinx.be&#34;&gt;http://www.davybuntinx.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>