<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pancake on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/pancake/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pancake on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/pancake/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony Nex-5, hands-on Review</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20101003_sony-nx-5-hands-on-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20101003_sony-nx-5-hands-on-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was given the samsung NX10 to test for 10 days, I was also handed a sony nex-5 a couple of weeks ago to play with it for one week. I&amp;rsquo;ve been postponing posting about this camera, because to be honest I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like it. The problem is not that I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the format, the quality or the technical parts of it. Actually I was very excited about those beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why did I not like the camera, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t intuitive. I tried to get over it and carried it with me for the whole week. The menu is not very logical, when I got the camera, I popped in a sd-card and wanted to format the card before taking pictures. Too bad it took me over 5 minutes to locate the format option in the menu. Because once you are in the menu, there are several submenu&amp;rsquo;s but the problem is that they are located vertically below each other and the camera stops scrolling for a little bit once you reach the end of the first menu. So you assume you reached the end of the menu and need to continue in another menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to that I was very annoyed by the startup time, it takes the camera 3-4 seconds to be able to take a picture. That&amp;rsquo;s too long for me. When I turn on a camera I want to be able to use it and not wait and loose the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most annoying thing was the fact that once you entered either photo or video mode, you could not review the results of the other mode without going to the unlogical menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So overall the camera is very nice, it would have been a great competitor compared to the samsung NX10, but sadly enough I didn&amp;rsquo;t take a lot of pictures because after the first day I got just very annoyed with it. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope sony fixes the each of use for their next release of this camera, it has a lot of potential but I would not recommend the camera to a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>