<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Logitech Magic</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110930_logitech-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110930_logitech-magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I got invited to the logitech magic event in Belgium together with some other bloggers. We rode out to Arquennes about 30 minutes from Brussels in Henegouwen. On arrival we were greeted with a glass of champagne and a short explanation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/wim_wauters&#34; title=&#34;Wim Wauters, on Twitter&#34; rel=&#34;contact met&#34;&gt;@wimwauters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images&#34; width=&#34;455&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-178&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got a tour around all the different products and in the mean time, there was a contest organized. I saw some nice products, but the most are not suited for me, because I have a fondness of the keyboards and mice/trackpads from Apple. The keys are just nicer from apple then any other keyboard I have used. However the accessoires for the ipad were very interesting, sadly enough the most interesting ones, like the keyboard cover are not suited for my iPad 1. But I can understand why a company developing products for Apple lines, are developing for the current versions alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contest had a pretty interesting take, because Logitech and Hill and Knowlton anticipated that we would cheat.  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:-)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;So they had a guess question included, which was how many tweets with the logitechmagic tag would be posted between 20 and 22h during the evening. As everybody was working together on finding the answers to the questions this actually was the only relevant question to receive the prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The range of prices was impressive, there was a surround system with a value of 350 euro to mice of 30 euro. But at least everybody got a price. I managed to get a set of Logitech 600vi in-ear phones. I&amp;rsquo;m currently testing them and I have to say the are amazingly great. These earphones are from the ultimate ear line, which is the same product line where a lot of professional musician are wearing headphones from during their concerts. The pair Sara and I got have a price value of 109 euro, which for me is very steep. That price means I would have never bought them myself, because I have a very bad track record with headphones. They tend to lay around and get tangled, ripped, get loose connections and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These seem very nicely and sturdy designed, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how they handle my abuse in the long run. The sound experience is quite impressive. I get a wide range of tones without any distortion or scrambling. The nice part is that there is a whole range of foam and plastic tips so you can choose the ones that fit your ear very nicely. I have a rather small ear channel and most tips don&amp;rsquo;t fit my ears, but the ones with the logitech ear phones actually fit my ear quite comfortable. I&amp;rsquo;m wearing them already several hours in a row, without getting any problems with having them falling out of my ear or without any discomfort. So my initial experience with these in-ear phones is very positive. So thanks a lot Logitech for a quite expensive goodie of good quality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sony Nex-5, hands-on Review</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20101003_sony-nx-5-hands-on-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20101003_sony-nx-5-hands-on-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I was given the samsung NX10 to test for 10 days, I was also handed a sony nex-5 a couple of weeks ago to play with it for one week. I&amp;rsquo;ve been postponing posting about this camera, because to be honest I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like it. The problem is not that I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the format, the quality or the technical parts of it. Actually I was very excited about those beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why did I not like the camera, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t intuitive. I tried to get over it and carried it with me for the whole week. The menu is not very logical, when I got the camera, I popped in a sd-card and wanted to format the card before taking pictures. Too bad it took me over 5 minutes to locate the format option in the menu. Because once you are in the menu, there are several submenu&amp;rsquo;s but the problem is that they are located vertically below each other and the camera stops scrolling for a little bit once you reach the end of the first menu. So you assume you reached the end of the menu and need to continue in another menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to that I was very annoyed by the startup time, it takes the camera 3-4 seconds to be able to take a picture. That&amp;rsquo;s too long for me. When I turn on a camera I want to be able to use it and not wait and loose the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most annoying thing was the fact that once you entered either photo or video mode, you could not review the results of the other mode without going to the unlogical menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So overall the camera is very nice, it would have been a great competitor compared to the samsung NX10, but sadly enough I didn&amp;rsquo;t take a lot of pictures because after the first day I got just very annoyed with it. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope sony fixes the each of use for their next release of this camera, it has a lot of potential but I would not recommend the camera to a friend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual revolution and privacy</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100428_virtual-revolution-and-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100428_virtual-revolution-and-privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night &lt;a title=&#34;Canvas&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34; href=&#34;http://www.canvas.be/&#34;&gt;Canvas&lt;/a&gt; aired the third episode of &lt;a title=&#34;BBC&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34; href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk&#34;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s internet documentary &lt;a title=&#34;Virtual Revolution&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34; href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/virtualrevolution&#34;&gt;The Virtual Revolution&lt;/a&gt;. The virtual revolution was an an open and collaborative production, which encouraged the web audience to help shape the series. But not only that is what made the experience interactive, during the TV-show people were encouraged to tweet and start a discussion about the subject of that evening. Canvas does the same and even has a web only discussion panel after every episode. Although hugely interesting, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to talk about it, you can check it out yourself at the &lt;a title=&#34;The Virtual Revolution on Canvas&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34; href=&#34;http://programmas.canvas.be/the-virtual-revolution/&#34;&gt;Canvas-website&lt;/a&gt; or on twitter with the hashtag &lt;a title=&#34;#virtualrevolution on Canvas&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34; href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23virtualrevolution&#34;&gt;#virtualrevolution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While following the tweets I noticed that a lot of people are very naive about their data online. They seem to think that you can hide yourself forever behind a screenname and that facebook is evil, because of their privacy settings. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t always agree with the policy of facebook, you won&amp;rsquo;t hear me say that they are the only evil on today&amp;rsquo;s web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a certain point in the discussion someone, whom I&amp;rsquo;m not going to name, said, I don&amp;rsquo;t use my name on the web, so it will be very difficult to find out who I am. To prove that it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not only facebook that has a lot of data about you, I started by looking to the person&amp;rsquo;s twitter account, there was a .be domain listed, I looked at the registry data for the domain. I found out a name but not yet the one I needed. By coupling that name to his nickname in google, I found within 7 minutes his real name, location, profession, likes and marriage status. This all without the use of facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think, most people don&amp;rsquo;t realize what they are sharing and how easy it is to find that data. From the moment you are connected to the internet you are sharing a lot of information. You get personalized ads according to your search query, content of your mail, webpage you are visiting, location you are, &amp;#8230; Everything you do on the web is recorded somewhere, somehow. Not only on the web btw, just think what&amp;rsquo;s possible with fidelity cards or your bank card.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>