<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logitech on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/logitech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Logitech on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/logitech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>[Review] Logitech F540</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20120307_review-logitech-f540/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20120307_review-logitech-f540/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6796342627/&#34; title=&#34;[Samsung nx200] Logitech F540 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7168/6796342627_8e4fea1b01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[Samsung nx200] Logitech F540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing the xbox late at night, while my girlfriend is asleep, isn&amp;rsquo;t possible. So I asked Logitech if I could test out the Logitech F540 wireless headphones for game consoles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days later I had the headphones. After unpacking the rather neatly put together box, it was very easy hooking it up to the Xbox. You basically plugg 2 wires into the basestation. The power and the audio cable. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t be easier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After turning on the headphones and pushing the sync button on both the station and the headphones, all was set. I played several hours while wearing the headset and was very pleased with the battery life, about 10 play hours. The sound quality for me was great too, although I&amp;rsquo;m not really a sound guy, but heck it was decent enough to hear the rain fall in Oblivion which for me is all I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t really use the microphone in game, but it&amp;rsquo;s pleasing to hear yourself through the headphones when the mic is on, so you don&amp;rsquo;t scream when talking. I did try it once and it seemed to work decent enough, but I can&amp;rsquo;t really tell because none of the other players in the game bothered to talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most headphones are quite hard to wear after a while, because my ear gets pinched, but the F540 has cups that go all around your ear, not on your ear which is very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only big problem I had and what for me is kinda of a deal breaker, is that fact that I got loads of interference after a while. Especially when the Xbox was online over the wifi signal, I tried all solutions found on the web, but none really helped, except putting the transmitter at a 45 degrees angle, but that is not very handy when you need somebody to hold the transmitter while you are playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So overall, I like the headset a lot, but there are 2 things I didn&amp;rsquo;t like, one is that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t use digital audio on it, which is very annoying because our tv only has a headphones and digital out connection and the headphones is never surround and the second one was the interference I got from other devices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logitech Magic</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110930_logitech-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110930_logitech-magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I got invited to the logitech magic event in Belgium together with some other bloggers. We rode out to Arquennes about 30 minutes from Brussels in Henegouwen. On arrival we were greeted with a glass of champagne and a short explanation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/wim_wauters&#34; title=&#34;Wim Wauters, on Twitter&#34; rel=&#34;contact met&#34;&gt;@wimwauters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images&#34; width=&#34;455&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-178&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got a tour around all the different products and in the mean time, there was a contest organized. I saw some nice products, but the most are not suited for me, because I have a fondness of the keyboards and mice/trackpads from Apple. The keys are just nicer from apple then any other keyboard I have used. However the accessoires for the ipad were very interesting, sadly enough the most interesting ones, like the keyboard cover are not suited for my iPad 1. But I can understand why a company developing products for Apple lines, are developing for the current versions alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contest had a pretty interesting take, because Logitech and Hill and Knowlton anticipated that we would cheat.  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png&#34; alt=&#34;:-)&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;So they had a guess question included, which was how many tweets with the logitechmagic tag would be posted between 20 and 22h during the evening. As everybody was working together on finding the answers to the questions this actually was the only relevant question to receive the prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The range of prices was impressive, there was a surround system with a value of 350 euro to mice of 30 euro. But at least everybody got a price. I managed to get a set of Logitech 600vi in-ear phones. I&amp;rsquo;m currently testing them and I have to say the are amazingly great. These earphones are from the ultimate ear line, which is the same product line where a lot of professional musician are wearing headphones from during their concerts. The pair Sara and I got have a price value of 109 euro, which for me is very steep. That price means I would have never bought them myself, because I have a very bad track record with headphones. They tend to lay around and get tangled, ripped, get loose connections and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These seem very nicely and sturdy designed, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how they handle my abuse in the long run. The sound experience is quite impressive. I get a wide range of tones without any distortion or scrambling. The nice part is that there is a whole range of foam and plastic tips so you can choose the ones that fit your ear very nicely. I have a rather small ear channel and most tips don&amp;rsquo;t fit my ears, but the ones with the logitech ear phones actually fit my ear quite comfortable. I&amp;rsquo;m wearing them already several hours in a row, without getting any problems with having them falling out of my ear or without any discomfort. So my initial experience with these in-ear phones is very positive. So thanks a lot Logitech for a quite expensive goodie of good quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images.png&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/ultimate-ears-600vi-noise-isolating-headset-glamour-images.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>