<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backblaze Cloud Backup on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/backblaze-cloud-backup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Backblaze Cloud Backup on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/backblaze-cloud-backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>[review] Backblaze, cloud backup</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20130109_review-backblaze-cloud-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20130109_review-backblaze-cloud-backup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/logo_backblaze.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Backblaze&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;52&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-271&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started using computers, I have had a mixed relation with backups. They are too much hassle to deal with, they fail, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough space. But since the internet connections are able to handle all data I produce now, I decided to start using cloud backup. I&amp;rsquo;v chosen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com&#34; title=&#34;Online Backup &amp;#038; Data Backup Software&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Backblaze cloud backup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had and still have a fully installed and running local backup system. But it took me a while to figure out an easy way to have a offsite backup for my photography. The problem is that having an off site backup used to be a lot of work, I tried several ways, but never found a way that worked reliably and wasn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only easy way, was and still is by uploading everything, but the problem in Belgium was that there were up and download limits set by the providers. Even today on the &amp;#8220;unlimited&amp;#8221; packages there still is a kind of restriction, it is around 500 gb to 1TB a month depending on the area you live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-backblaze:e148ee00a4cf976b17c9ce8fe109987d&#34;&gt;Why Backblaze?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After extensively researching the different solutions, I decide to go with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com&#34; title=&#34;Online Backup &amp;#038; Data Backup Software&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;, because of the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup external drives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throttle upload speed of your data when needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship backup drives worldwide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only 4$ a month if you choose the 2 year plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlimited backup space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I found, there are no other services that offer all these options for that money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-does-it-work:e148ee00a4cf976b17c9ce8fe109987d&#34;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works great, after subscribing and paying with your credit card, you download and install the program for your OS. Backblaze will start to upload data from your internal drives. If you want to add more drives, just select it in the preferences pane. If you have upload limits, you can choose to throttle the speed and Blackblaze gives you an estimate how much it will upload during a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few figures to give you an idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.2 TB data backed up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial backup took 3.5 months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored main OS X data once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restored 35 GB in a zip-file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;is-it-good:e148ee00a4cf976b17c9ce8fe109987d&#34;&gt;Is it good?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it took almost 4 months of backing up, it was no hassle, Backblaze just worked. Restoring was just a matter of selecting the files I wanted, waiting for the zip to be generated and then downloading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not all good, the restore process sucks. You&amp;rsquo;ll get all your files back, but it&amp;rsquo;s up to you to put them all back where they belong. That&amp;rsquo;s no fun, let me tell you. You have to deal with permissions, finding the correct folder and so on. Another annoyance, is the fact that after the restore, my secondary internal drive was no longer recognized as being the same drive, so it had to be backed up again, like the replaced primary drive. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion:e148ee00a4cf976b17c9ce8fe109987d&#34;&gt;Conclusion?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backblaze is a great solution for an off site backup, but it takes a while to get all your data backed up, my suggestion let me send you guys a drive with my data for an extra cost, like crashplan does. When you have to restore, it&amp;rsquo;s all manual labour. I would suggest that they implement some sort of restore program that does most of the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the remarks I have, I&amp;rsquo;m a satisfied &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backblaze.com&#34; title=&#34;Online Backup &amp;#038; Data Backup Software&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Backblaze cloud backup&lt;/a&gt; user and would recommend it to everybody&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wasn’t forced to write this blogpost, everything in here is my own view, the content wasn’t reviewed by any departement of the brands mentioned in here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/logo_backblaze.gif&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/logo_backblaze.gif&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>