<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3k Hyperx on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/3k-hyperx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3k Hyperx on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/3k-hyperx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>[review] Kingston 3K hyperX SSD</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20121020_review-kingston-3k-hyperx-ssd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20121020_review-kingston-3k-hyperx-ssd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: after 5 months this Kingston 3K hyperX SSD completely died on me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/hyperx.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kingston 3K HyperX SSD&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-267&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of june, my girflfriend (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saravdv.be&#34; rel=&#34;friend muse&#34; title=&#34;Saravdv: there are no endings, only new beginnings&#34;&gt;SaraVdV&lt;/a&gt;) got a mail from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kingston.com&#34; title=&#34;Kingston Technology&#34; rel=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Kingston&lt;/a&gt; if she and I wanted to test a new SSD drive from Kingston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some mailing back and forth, because Sara and I both work on mac&amp;rsquo;s, Kingston send us both a 256GB HyperX 3K SSD drive. It comes in a nice package, with an external usb enclosure and it&amp;rsquo;s own screwdriver. Which is always very handy. The drives we received were 2.5&amp;#8243; drives, but included in the package you buy, there&amp;rsquo;s also a 3.5&amp;#8243; bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it would be easier from me to put the drive in the MacBook pro 15&amp;#8243; begin 2009 I have, than to put it in an iMac. I started with that computer, the drive is as easy to install as any drive. However when I booted the mac and started installing OS X I ran into some problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first the install of OS X stalled a couple of times, when I finally managed to install it correctly, I had a 25 sec spinning beachball every 2 minutes. However, because we had review drives, I contacted Kingston directly and started to work out the problem with Mario, on of the engineers at Kingston who developed the drive. Turns out that there is an incompatibility between the nvidia SATA I controller in the MacBook 5.1 and the driver for SATA II or III SSD&amp;rsquo;s in OS X leopard or later. This makes that every time there is a lot of writing activity to the disk that the controller locks the OS for a while untill the buffers are cleared. So I ended up restoring this MacBook to it&amp;rsquo;s original config. This is not a fault of the kingston drive but an Apple problem, because I also experienced the same behaviour with another brand of SSD&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my debacle with the drive in the Macbook 5.1, I also installed the drive in Sara&amp;rsquo;s iMac which is not too big of a hassle if you follow all the guides online for replacing a drive in an iMac. I have not had any problems with installing the drive and reinstalling OS X, nor has Sara experienced any problems since the drive was installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July I purchased myself a new 13&amp;#8243; MacBook pro and installed the HyperX SSD in that computer. No problems, everything installs and works perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performance wise, everything seems a lot quicker on the iMac of Sara, boot times improved a lot. Every program launches faster and the drive behaves very well under pressure. We didn&amp;rsquo;t do any graphs or charts, because in the end it all comes down to how you preceive the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the MacBook 13&amp;#8243; I did some testing. Without SSD it cold booted in 34 seconds, after install of the SSD it cold boots in 8secs. That&amp;rsquo;s just amazing. It feels more instant now then waking my iPad first generation from sleep. Programs are launching very fast, lightroom which is the most important program for me, launches in less then 3 seconds in grid view. It all feels very snappy and instant. I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a beachball in months. Reboots are only necessary for updates from the OS. It just works and feels fast. It does what I expected an SSD to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nicest surprise is that we may keep the drives, so I got a nice upgrade for my new MacBook thanks to Kingston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t forced to write this blogpost, everything in here is my own view, the content wasn&amp;rsquo;t reviewed by any departement of the brands mentioned in here. I did however receive a compensation for this post. So decide for yourself how much value you want to attribute to this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/hyperx.jpg&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/hyperx.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>