<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>[Tutorial] Setting up WDS with Apple airports</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20120130_tutorial-setting-up-wds-with-apple-airports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20120130_tutorial-setting-up-wds-with-apple-airports/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE: in minutes of me posting this tutorial, my airport utility got an update to v6.0 and all I said is obsolete, my WDS network still works, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet how to set it up correctly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-11.46.31.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-11.46.31.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Airport_admin_utility&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-197&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over here we have a nice setup for our wireless network and playing music in all the rooms of our house. It&amp;rsquo;s supported by Apple airports. As you can see in the above screenshot. We use an Airport extreme as the router and 3 Airport expresses as relays. Last saturday evening however, disaster struck and our Airport extreme died. Well it did not die completely, it stopped serving internet through the wifi connections and there was only connection via ethernet connections. The wifi clients however could still connect, authenticate and got an ip-address, but there it all stopped. I tried everything to restore the connections, but despite all my efforts for about 3 hours. Rebooting, resetting, hard resetting nothing worked. So I setup a temporary solution and went out today to get a new Airport extreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get to the technical part of this article. How do you setup a network of 4 airports across the house on the same network with wpa2 security enabled? The first and most important step is to hard reset all the airports, the only way to do that if the airports don&amp;rsquo;t come straight from the box is to hold down the little reset button while pluggin in the airport. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know how, check this &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.apple.com/kb/ht3728&#34; title=&#34;Reset airport&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;support-page&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/&#34; title=&#34;Apple website&#34; rel=&#34;none&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;configure-the-base-station-or-wds-main:f0747a94ba74626be30e9712b67e6fe6&#34;&gt;Configure the base station or WDS main&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start by selecting manual configuration in the airport utility, don&amp;rsquo;t use the wizard, as you will not be able to setup WDS. On the next screen, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a couple of tabs, but none of them shows WDS, at least when you have a recent airport extreme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now setup your Base Station like always, fill out the name, choose a password, &amp;#8230; under the Base Station tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next tab is the Wireless tab, this is 1 of the 2 tabs where all the magic will happen.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-21.35.43.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-21.35.43.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2012-01-30 at 21.35.43&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-203&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In the dropdown menu next to &amp;#8220;Wireless Mode&amp;#8221; select &amp;#8220;Participate in a WDS network&amp;#8221;, if you don&amp;rsquo;t see it, hold down the &amp;#8220;option&amp;#8221; key, it will magically appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You setup your network as always, but make sure you select the checkbox &amp;#8220;Allow this network to be extended&amp;#8221;, leave the Radio mode on Automatic, choose WPA/WPA2 Personal, choose a password, go to the Wireless Network Options, set your country and leave all the rest. (&lt;em&gt;Hint:&lt;/em&gt; Write down all settings, we&amp;rsquo;ll need them later)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next is the WDS tab, that has appeared after you selected &amp;#8220;Participate in a WDS network&amp;#8221; in the previous step. Select &amp;#8220;WDS main&amp;#8221; in the dropdown from &amp;#8220;WDS Mode&amp;#8221;. Select the checkbox next to &amp;#8220;Allow wireless clients&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-21.47.50.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-21.47.50.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2012-01-30 at 21.47.50&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-209&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fill in the Airport ID&amp;rsquo;s of the soon to be remotes, you find the airport ID&amp;rsquo;s on the bottom of the airport it should be a string of 12 alphanumeric characters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That are all the steps for the configuring the base station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;configure-the-wds-remotes:f0747a94ba74626be30e9712b67e6fe6&#34;&gt;Configure the WDS remotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For configuring the remotes, repeat steps 1 till 3 exactly as in configuring the WDS main station. Make sure you have all the wireless settings exactly the same, as for the WDS main station. Make sure you did not miss any setting and if you must choose a channel set it to 11, because otherwise the remote station can&amp;rsquo;t connect with the WDS main.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-22.16.46.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Screen Shot 2012-01-30 at 22.16.46&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-211&#34; /&gt;][4]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To finish the setup, go to the WDS tab and choose for &amp;#8220;WDS remote&amp;#8221; in the drop down next to &amp;#8220;WDS Mode&amp;#8221;. Select the checkbox next to &amp;#8220;Allow wireless clients&amp;#8221; and fill in the Airport ID of the &amp;#8220;WDS main&amp;#8221;, update and test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repeat the steps for the airport remote for as many times you need it. You should now be able to use the network and if you activated airplay under &amp;#8220;Music&amp;#8221; you should be able to play music through every airport with boxes or a headphone connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A last piece of advice, if you configured a airport and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t connect or shows up, put in a ethernet cable so that you can access it again. This will save you a lot of time, because the only other option is hard resetting the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-22.16.46.png&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-Shot-2012-01-30-at-22.16.46.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of an era: Steve Jobs</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110825_the-end-of-an-era-steve-jobs-steps-down-as-ceo-of-apple-inc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110825_the-end-of-an-era-steve-jobs-steps-down-as-ceo-of-apple-inc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/steve-jobs1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;steve-jobs1&#34; width=&#34;229&#34; height=&#34;287&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-170&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a huge Apple fanboy, it&amp;rsquo;s a very sad day for me. Steve Jobs just announced his resignation as a CEO of Apple inc. Below you find the most significant part from his resignation letter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always said if there ever came a day when I could no longer meet my duties and expectations as Apple’s CEO, I would be the first to let you know. Unfortunately, that day has come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steve Jobs &amp;#8211; Resignation Letter august 24, 2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that Steve&amp;rsquo;s health was on a bad streak, starting with his pancreas cancer in 2006, his liver transplant in 2009 and the indefinite leave of absence due to health issues. Every keynote we saw a sleeker and sleeker Steve at this rate, he would be no more than a skeleton by the release of the iPhone 6. But I hoped that Steve would recover and kick some more butt in the years to come. Sadly that won&amp;rsquo;t be true anymore. Let&amp;rsquo;s just hope, that Steve can now focus on his health a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I say, the end of an era? A look at his track record, which reads like a good novel and is a string of successes, says it all. The story starts in 1976 with the release of the Apple I, a computer built in a garage by 2 very young guys, dreaming that one day they could earn a profit from it. Little would they know that was the beginning of a dream come true. Although Wozniak left Apple and Jobs was fired in the nineties and hired back afterwards, in which time he founded, build and make Pixar huge. Now Apple not only has produced great products, but it has also become the biggest company in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Jobs now resigning as CEO I still believe in Apple and they will keep on producing great products, but there won&amp;rsquo;t be anymore iconic black turtle necks, no more casual &amp;#8220;There&amp;rsquo;s one more thing&amp;#8221; to drop a bomb on a market. I fear that the cult of mac, will no longer exist, it has lost it leader. Apple will probably become a dull company that still makes great products, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t have me sitting in suspense during a keynote what they will announce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off course Jobs is not without fault, I&amp;rsquo;m the first to admit it, but he is kind of a hero for me. Creating a company from scratch and making it this big, but still maintaining the suspense when announcing something new. There is no other company that I know of where one man had such an impact on the development, announcement and sales of a product that nobody needed before it was announced. It also takes a great man, to resign due to health reasons from the company you built from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that one day, I can look back at my life and say I made an impact, as did Steve Jobs, my personal hero business wise. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t has to be as significant as Steve&amp;rsquo;s impact, but I would like to know that I have done well according to my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So hereby I salute you, Steve, you are a great man and leader. Take care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/steve-jobs1.jpeg&#34;&gt;http://www.achter.be/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/steve-jobs1.jpeg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An applefanboy’s wet dream</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110303_an-applefanboys-wet-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110303_an-applefanboys-wet-dream/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/iphone_bunker/5492665031/&#34; title=&#34;Woot woot. @saravdv and I in tje video during the apple keynote #realapplefans by Bunker&#39;s iphone, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5054/5492665031_bab549732c.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Woot woot. @saravdv and I in tje video during the apple keynote #realapplefans&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year when &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saravdv.be&#34; title=&#34;Saravdv, there are no endings only new beginnings&#34; rel=&#34;muse met&#34;&gt;Saravdv&lt;/a&gt; and I went to Paris for the iPad launch at the louvre Apple store, we were asked if we could be filmed for a possible promo film for Apple. As we got some iTunes gift cards in exchange, we did agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then we did not hear anything about it anymore, until last night when I watched the keynote, to my surprise I could see sara and myself during the video of &amp;#8220;2010: the year of the iPad.&amp;#8221; as I&amp;rsquo;m a very big applefanboy, I&amp;rsquo;m quite proud to be in the video that his Steveness showed during a keynote. If you want to check it out, watch the keynote at [Apple event website][2]. You can see us very briefly at 9:49 min in the keynote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update, you can also watch the video of &amp;#8220;iPad: Year One&amp;#8221; on Apple&amp;rsquo;s YouTube channel. I have embedded the video also here, you can see Sara and me at 0:35min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/fv9o83&#34;&gt;http://bit.ly/fv9o83&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The iPad revolution</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100609_the-ipad-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100609_the-ipad-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;ve used my iPad for 12 days and I love it even more then I did the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love catching up with my RSS feeds, reading and replying to e-mails, writing blogposts and booking a hotel. The size of the screen makes it a great device for presenting pictures and watching series or movies streamed from my MBP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typing on the ipad is actually pretty good, you can&amp;rsquo;t use your regular typing position but typing with 6 fingers works very well. It&amp;rsquo;s just an awesome device to use all the time and everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are a few small things that annoy me. First of all Apple should have included some way to prop up the iPad when resting it in your lap or putting it on the table to type with 2 hands. Now I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a way to elevate it a bit and most of the time I&amp;rsquo;m putting my wallet under it, because that&amp;rsquo;s the perfect height and doesn&amp;rsquo;t slip. But at the moment I did not find any great case yet. I would love the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dodocase.com&#34;&gt;DODO case&lt;/a&gt; but they are backordered for 4 to 6 weeks and they are missing a nice height for watching movies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another annoying thing is that at the moment there is no Twitter client that I like and definitely no app that satisfies my needs for google reader, but off course there&amp;rsquo;s an app for that at least over time there will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most annoying thing is taking it out of your bag in Belgium. once you take it out to usef it, there&amp;rsquo;s always somebody who starts saying that there are better things to use, you can&amp;rsquo;t do this or that,&amp;#8230; Basically I like my iPad, it serves the purpose where I bought it for, so just let me use it and don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m taking it out to brag, I just want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m going to stop this blogpost so I can watch [chase jarvis live][2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chasejarvis.com/live&#34;&gt;http://www.chasejarvis.com/live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>road trip to Paris</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100528_road-trip-to-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100528_road-trip-to-paris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had some crazy ideas before and I&amp;rsquo;ve build quite a reputation of opening shops of my favourite brands and queueing for gadgets. When, last January I saw Steve jobs unveil the iPad, I was sold. I also knew I would be queueing for it when it became available in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today was the day of the official release for the iPad In France. in the past days I have been researching a lot about the release on the internet. Well actually I was researching it with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pietervanimpe.com&#34; rel=&#34;friend collegue met&#34; title=&#34;Pieter Van Impe&#34;&gt;Pieter&lt;/a&gt;, we first thought of going to the fnac in Lille. It turned we could be left without an iPad to buy, so we decided to go to Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight at midnight we left for Paris accompanied by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saravdv.be&#34;&gt;Sara&lt;/a&gt; and [Davy][2]. We arrived at 3h30 and found a parking spot surprisingly easy just around the corner of the apple store. There were already 6 people in front of us, but at least we knew we would have an iPad and so the waiting began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the hour got closer, Pieter and I were wondering about which one we would get, while Sara was deciding if she would get one. Unfortunately we didn&amp;rsquo;t have all the time waiting to decide because the press found out that there were some crazy Belgians in the queue. Most of them wanted to talk to us. We gave some interviews and were asked by a production crew of Apple to be followed while and after buying the iPad. We even got an iTunes gift certificate of 15€ out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t found all the links to the videos and articles yet but I&amp;rsquo;ll add them once I&amp;rsquo;ve found them.&amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is typed on the iPad and I found it pretty pleasing to type a small blogpost like this one in the WP app. After playing with it for the last hour I&amp;rsquo;m even more convinced that I wanted this device. I&amp;rsquo;ll write a review and some app recommendations later aft i used it for an extended time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davybuntinx.be&#34;&gt;http://www.davybuntinx.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>