<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ipad on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/ipad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ipad on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/ipad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The iPad revolution</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100609_the-ipad-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100609_the-ipad-revolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;ve used my iPad for 12 days and I love it even more then I did the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love catching up with my RSS feeds, reading and replying to e-mails, writing blogposts and booking a hotel. The size of the screen makes it a great device for presenting pictures and watching series or movies streamed from my MBP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typing on the ipad is actually pretty good, you can&amp;rsquo;t use your regular typing position but typing with 6 fingers works very well. It&amp;rsquo;s just an awesome device to use all the time and everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are a few small things that annoy me. First of all Apple should have included some way to prop up the iPad when resting it in your lap or putting it on the table to type with 2 hands. Now I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a way to elevate it a bit and most of the time I&amp;rsquo;m putting my wallet under it, because that&amp;rsquo;s the perfect height and doesn&amp;rsquo;t slip. But at the moment I did not find any great case yet. I would love the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dodocase.com&#34;&gt;DODO case&lt;/a&gt; but they are backordered for 4 to 6 weeks and they are missing a nice height for watching movies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another annoying thing is that at the moment there is no Twitter client that I like and definitely no app that satisfies my needs for google reader, but off course there&amp;rsquo;s an app for that at least over time there will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most annoying thing is taking it out of your bag in Belgium. once you take it out to usef it, there&amp;rsquo;s always somebody who starts saying that there are better things to use, you can&amp;rsquo;t do this or that,&amp;#8230; Basically I like my iPad, it serves the purpose where I bought it for, so just let me use it and don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m taking it out to brag, I just want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m going to stop this blogpost so I can watch [chase jarvis live][2]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chasejarvis.com/live&#34;&gt;http://www.chasejarvis.com/live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>road trip to Paris</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100528_road-trip-to-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100528_road-trip-to-paris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had some crazy ideas before and I&amp;rsquo;ve build quite a reputation of opening shops of my favourite brands and queueing for gadgets. When, last January I saw Steve jobs unveil the iPad, I was sold. I also knew I would be queueing for it when it became available in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So today was the day of the official release for the iPad In France. in the past days I have been researching a lot about the release on the internet. Well actually I was researching it with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pietervanimpe.com&#34; rel=&#34;friend collegue met&#34; title=&#34;Pieter Van Impe&#34;&gt;Pieter&lt;/a&gt;, we first thought of going to the fnac in Lille. It turned we could be left without an iPad to buy, so we decided to go to Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight at midnight we left for Paris accompanied by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.saravdv.be&#34;&gt;Sara&lt;/a&gt; and [Davy][2]. We arrived at 3h30 and found a parking spot surprisingly easy just around the corner of the apple store. There were already 6 people in front of us, but at least we knew we would have an iPad and so the waiting began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the hour got closer, Pieter and I were wondering about which one we would get, while Sara was deciding if she would get one. Unfortunately we didn&amp;rsquo;t have all the time waiting to decide because the press found out that there were some crazy Belgians in the queue. Most of them wanted to talk to us. We gave some interviews and were asked by a production crew of Apple to be followed while and after buying the iPad. We even got an iTunes gift certificate of 15€ out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t found all the links to the videos and articles yet but I&amp;rsquo;ll add them once I&amp;rsquo;ve found them.&amp;lt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is typed on the iPad and I found it pretty pleasing to type a small blogpost like this one in the WP app. After playing with it for the last hour I&amp;rsquo;m even more convinced that I wanted this device. I&amp;rsquo;ll write a review and some app recommendations later aft i used it for an extended time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davybuntinx.be&#34;&gt;http://www.davybuntinx.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>