<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Samsung on achter.be</title>
    <link>http://www.achter.be/tags/samsung/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Samsung on achter.be</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.achter.be/tags/samsung/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>[Review] Samsung NX200</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20120206_review-samsung-nx200/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20120206_review-samsung-nx200/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://500px.com/photo/4714308&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://pcdn.500px.net/4714308/cc7bd653dc8402e2871aee39975ca5463fa1f52b/4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;[Samsung nx200] Long exposures by Filip Bunkens (Pitslamp)) on 500px.com&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a professional photographer, I get to test new cameras when they are released. That&amp;rsquo;s how I got my hands on a Samsung NX200 for a couple of months now. This review is going to from a professional viewpoint, if you want a less technical review check out my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pitslamp.com/blog/20120131_samsung_nx200&#34; title=&#34;Samsung NX200 review | PitsLamp&#34;&gt;PitsLamp blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nx200 is a mirror less camera system, with some pretty decent lenses. I&amp;rsquo;ll list the pro and cons of the camera and will explain some a bit lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pro&#34;&gt;Pro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pretty high fps in RAW (4) even higher in JPEG (7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nice intuitive interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hot shoe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very accessible buttons on the right locations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good quality AMOLED display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 MP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good form factor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;con&#34;&gt;Con&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lot&amp;rsquo;s of noise above ISO 800&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slow startup time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No viewfinder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No swiveling display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the very short version of my likes and dislikes of the Samsung NX200. So now let me get into that in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;screen&#34;&gt;Screen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the screen is great, even in harsh sunlight. However, because of no viewfinder and no swiveling screen, it&amp;rsquo;s not always very easy to compose a shot. You are limited to how you can look at the screen. This means no shots low by the ground, or high above your head, because composing is not possible if you don&amp;rsquo;t see the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ease-of-use&#34;&gt;Ease of use&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samsung always had a pretty good idea how to make a camera easy to use. The menu is clear, easy, logical. All the buttons are located very conveniently, at least for me they are. It&amp;rsquo;s a joy to use this camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However how hard Samsung keeps on trying to have me use the i-Function button on the lens, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care for it. It&amp;rsquo;s is one of their selling points since the nx100, it was made after the older rangefinder cameras where you could set almost everything on the lens. But where Samsung got it wrong for me, is that the button is never in the same place on the lenses. Also the first you use the button it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really react directly. Also the ring on the lens you can use to change the settings, is stepless, but the interface on the screen has steps, that&amp;rsquo;s confusing. So I prefer to use the buttons on top and on the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quality-and-speed&#34;&gt;Quality and speed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A slow startup speed, makes that you better don&amp;rsquo;t use the battery saving feature, if you want to photograph your kids, make sure you keep it on all the time. However once started, the speed is very good, a very decent fps even in RAW. On the other hand, once you want to look at the photos, it can take quite some time before the RAW&amp;rsquo;s are processed. So speed overall is not good enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/6796342627/&#34; title=&#34;[Samsung nx200] Logitech F540 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7168/6796342627_8e4fea1b01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[Samsung nx200] Logitech F540&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 20MP on the camera, the photos are of good quality, large, nice to look at in 100%. The camera is excellent for studio work in tight spaces, I did love it for product shots, especially with the 60mm macro lens. The hot shoe makes it possible to use radio triggers which again is awesome for studio shoots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a very big drawback, as with the first DSLR&amp;rsquo;s the camera, absolutely doesn&amp;rsquo;t perform well in low light conditions. For me in color the photos until 800 iso are acceptable, in b/w you can go up till 1600 but after that you&amp;rsquo;re out of luck. Too much noise, especially color noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have mixed feelings about this camera. I do like the interface, but I don&amp;rsquo;t like the quality of the photos. So if you are looking for a small, interchangeable camera with most use being during the day or in studio settings, definitely go for it. If you are looking for an allround camera, don&amp;rsquo;t go for this one, there are better alternatives out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of the Samsung Navibot VCR8855</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20110127_review-of-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20110127_review-of-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After more than 2 months using the Navibot, I want to give you a review. Let me say, we&amp;rsquo;re pretty pleased with the Robot vacuum cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it&amp;rsquo;s not a total solution for cleaning, it does a very good job keeping the house clean, when you set it on a daily routine. It takes a structured path, which takes it through the most part of the room. During it&amp;rsquo;s path, it tries to cover the whole area, but misses some spots. Luckily it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take the same path everyday and does the missed spots the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a week we empty the container containing the dust and hairs,. So it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require a lot of maintanance but whenever you forget about putting away all toys for the cat or the floorcloths, we use as doormats, something is bound to get stuck in the rotating brushes. Then the robot stops and starts beeping, until you fix the problem, that&amp;rsquo;s annoying and drives our cat crazy when we aren&amp;rsquo;t at home. But apart from that, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get trapped under furniture, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t wrecks anything around the home. It only bumps into the furniture that has legs that are smaller than 5cm because it is in the blind spot of the sensors. Even when it does bump into your furniture, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really damages it, because of the rubber bumpers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only very annoying thing about the robot is whenever you use the guards, it gets confused because the beam of the guard spreads wider then you intend and that leaves areas around the guard without cleaning. Our robot also had a little defect, which broke the system that makes the back brush rotate and we had to send it in for repair. Since then it drives around and cleans the whole area very good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a decent robot vacuum cleaner, then this is definitely what you need. It does a really good job keeping the house clean, without you lifting a finger, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not perfect but it&amp;rsquo;s a great aid. For us it is a great tool and definitely cheaper than paying a cleaning lady. So yes, it&amp;rsquo;s an expensive buy, but it will pay off after a while, because maintenance is not expensive at all. Even after 2 months we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to change any of the brushes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unboxing the Samsung Navibot VCR8855</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20101107_unboxing-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20101107_unboxing-the-samsung-navibot-vcr8855/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After moving from our apartment to a house we vey fast figured out that we had a lot more cleaning to do. Let that be one of our weak spots in the household. So we started thinking about a cleaning lady, but that turned out pretty expensive if you start looking at a longterm solution. So we decided we would buy a robot cleaner to at least vacuum the place every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started looking online for reviews and different types. It turns out there are only 2 different manufacturers of robot cleaners, the one we all know, iRobot with the roomba and Samsung with their navibots. There doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be a great difference between the different manufacturers at first sight. So why did we choose the navibot instead of a roomba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cat looses a lot of very fine hair so we needed a robot that could deal with that problem. After reading a lot of reviews and watching some YouTube videos about the different models, we decided that we needed the roomba pet series or the navibot VCR8855. So we went to the shop to actually see the robots. We didn&amp;rsquo;t find a roomba pet series in the shop, but we could examine the 555 series. After talking to the person responsible for the robot vacuum cleaners at vandenborre, the thing that made us decide is the difference in cleaning. The roombas wander around randomly while the navibot follows a structured path, to clean. So in our opinion the navibot cleans more thorough and more like we humans do. Although the navibot costs 499, euro vs 429 euro for the roomba, but with the navibot you get more accessories, but you&amp;rsquo;ll find that out in the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only time will tell if the navibot works for us, but that is the subject of another post. So now without further ado here is the unboxing video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/16573688&#34;&gt;Unboxing a Samsung Navibot VCR8855&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/pitslamp&#34;&gt;PitsLamp&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samsung NX10, hands on review</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100721_samsung-nx10-hands-on-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100721_samsung-nx10-hands-on-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I had the opportunity to play with the Samsung NX10 camera. As said in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.achter.be/20100620_samsung-nx10/&#34; title=&#34;Samsung NX10&#34;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt; I really liked the camera and that didn&amp;rsquo;t change during the 10 days I was allowed to use it. I even wanted to keep the camera with the 20mm pancake lens. Just because it is such an amazing small and convenient camera, it can go anywhere with you and it delivers great results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the NX10 to shoot some behind the scene material during a wedding with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bertstephani.com&#34;&gt;Bert Stephani&lt;/a&gt;. The photos are taken with the 20mm pancake lens and as jpeg in monochrome mode. The results are very good and I like the speed, the sharpness and the fast focus it has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791201689/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4141/4791201689_b7156075c9.jpg&#34; width=&#34;333&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791202209/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4095/4791202209_1e48ba34f7.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791203085/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4119/4791203085_ab5304223e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also tried the NX10 during the &amp;#8220;dijlefeesten&amp;#8221; festival in my hometown and during some other low light conditions. The results are quite exceptional, the noise is very acceptable, that&amp;rsquo;s mainly because of the large sensor, it&amp;rsquo;s actually only a 1.5 crop factor. But not only the noise is very acceptable, the autofocus is also very good and fast even with the lights on stage flooding the frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791838302/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4141/4791838302_4cc8a52c73.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791208367/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4099/4791208367_978509c572.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/loneblackrider/4791840000/&#34; title=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10 by PitsLamp photography, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4143/4791840000_dbb4c00656.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;[camera-test] Samsung NX10&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can keep on talking about the technical stuff of this camera. Samsung had to make some compromises to keep the camera small but the experience with this camera is just great, I mean it just awesome to use, it&amp;rsquo;s small, fast, easy to use, but most of all it&amp;rsquo;s fun to use. Samsung keep up the good work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>samsung 3D Tv</title>
      <link>http://www.achter.be/20100531_samsung-3d-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.achter.be/20100531_samsung-3d-tv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m invited at the launch of the 3D tv in Brussels. I&amp;rsquo;m live blogging from the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start we have Bruno Tassert, product manager at Samsung. He&amp;rsquo;s giving a product overview of the 3D collection of Samsung. It started in the eighties but with the clumsy glasses in cardboard it was not a real success. Until the film avatar last year 3D stayed without success. Today 3D is possible because the technology permits it. The movie studios have adopted the technology and now it&amp;rsquo;s time for the consumer to use 3D in their own homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3D is basically two images who are projected next to each other. At first in 2 different colors but now the technology has evolved and uses different polarities in the glasses, this is the way it is used by the movie theaters, it&amp;rsquo;s passive. The tech used in the in the samsung tv is with an active component in the glasses. One side is just shown on TV the other one is shown and filtered by the glasses. This technology uses 200mhz. This is called the shutter technique. The last way is like the photos in 3D which has the big disadvantage that you can&amp;rsquo;t look at it from a side and the 2D experience really sucks. Although they all have their disadvantages, the shutter technique is the only one that makes it possible to show HD content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you would expect you can put the 2 different images side by side or on top of each other. Now we are getting in to the really technical stuff, so I&amp;rsquo;m just going to skip that part if you want more info about it, you can search for it yourself on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to choose for Samsung, according to them because they launched 3D as first and have all the other devices ready for it. But the most important reason is because they use conversion by object based depth processing, while the other ways of 3D just separate the objects in a vertical direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 3D you only need a television, a blue Ray player and off course the glasses. There are 3 different types at the moment, ranging from 2000 to 5000+ euro for the LCD and LED. But they also have plasma. Next to that they also have the blue Ray player and the 3D home cinema. The glasses range from 79 euro for the children glasses and going up to 99 euro for the adult version. There are 2 sizes in adult sizes, because not everybody has the same face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content is available from movies, games like avatar which we can test here and there are a couple of channels that start their emissions in 3D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we arrive at the real history of 3D, in 1857 the first real 3D machine was build, in the 1950&amp;rsquo;s there were already about 60 movies released in 3D, but it was a real PITA to watch a full length movie. In the sixties they tried some 3D in color but it still didn&amp;rsquo;t work, after another try with Jaws they left the idea for a while. The first real 3D were the Imax movies in theme parks. That worked but it was very expensive and time consuming to make Imax movies. We had to wait till this century before they started to do some new things in 3D, where they started again with animation films and the real breakthrough was reached last summer with the release of several 3D movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we get a overview of what they showed in the Belgian pavilion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2005 they 5 biggest directors in Hollywood announced at DLP that 3D would be the future for the movies because that way it was almost impossible to pirate. Philips started with a project for 3D without glasses but had to stop production because it was too heavy, big and there was not enough quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are apparently 2 different ways of filming, one is crossing the cameras, that&amp;rsquo;s what is used by Cameron in Avatar. The other way is, like it&amp;rsquo;s mainly used in Europe is by aligning the cameras parrallel which makes the images pop more. But on infinity it everything is in focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have something to eat and will all participate in a quiz later on. My opinion on the whole experience I&amp;rsquo;ll post later with some pictures. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>